<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tony Locke - 2019</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.tlocke.org.uk/feeds/2019.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Freud? Hasn't he been shown to be wrong?</title><link href="/freud-hasnt-he-been-shown-to-be-wrong.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony Locke</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-07-17:/freud-hasnt-he-been-shown-to-be-wrong.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just finished reading Mark Edmundson's
&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2007/sep/01/biography.society"&gt;The Death Of Sigmund Freud (Fascism, Psychoanalysis and the Rise of
Fundamentalism)&lt;/a&gt;. If ever I
mention Freud, people say, "Freud? Hasn't he been shown to be wrong?". Over the
years I've read this and that by Freud or about him and he was a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just finished reading Mark Edmundson's
&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2007/sep/01/biography.society"&gt;The Death Of Sigmund Freud (Fascism, Psychoanalysis and the Rise of
Fundamentalism)&lt;/a&gt;. If ever I
mention Freud, people say, "Freud? Hasn't he been shown to be wrong?". Over the
years I've read this and that by Freud or about him and he was a great
wellspring of intelligent, original ideas. He was fearless in his thinking,
and didn't recoil from publishing ideas that were shocking to society. The
reader does have to pick out the ones that are actually true though. I say that
I've read about Freud, but as Edmundson says about Hitler, 'he read a great
deal, but it's not at all clear that he understood much of what he read'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Freud%27s_couch,_London,_2004_(2%29.jpeg#/media/File:Freud's_couch,_London,_2004_(2%29.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Freud's couch, London, 2004 (2).jpeg" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/9/96/Freud%27s_couch%2C_London%2C_2004_%282%29.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Photo by ROBERT HUFFSTUTTER -
&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0"&gt;CC BY 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, here is my view of the three most important things I think Freud
was right about: the unconscious mind, the cause of neurosis, the cure for neurosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking those in turn, the unconscious was central to Freud's ideas, and is now
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unconscious_mind#Contemporary_cognitive_psychology"&gt;well established by modern science&lt;/a&gt;. In a nutshell, the unconscious mind works away beneath one's awareness, but
can determine much of one's behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freud thought that neurosis was caused by a breakdown in communication between
the conscious and unconscious mind. Certain events, ideas, feelings etc are
'repressed', that is they are trapped in the unconscious, and the conscious mind
lacks access to them. Being cut off from parts of oneself was held by Freud to
be the cause of neurosis. Is it true that this is the cause of neurosis? I
think the scientific evidence leaves this question open. For myself, I am
persuaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final idea of Freud is that communication between the conscious and unconscious can be restored, and repressed thoughts, feelings etc. can be processed and become accessible again to the conscious mind. The route to doing this is the
'talking cure'. A therapist can provide a space for non-judgemental listening,
where the client tries to be as uninhibited as possible about what they are
saying and gradually hitherto unconscious material rises to the surface.
Dreams are also thought to be a way in which the unconscious mind communicates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So does the talking cure work? Again, this is controversial. I'm inclined to
think it is beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>France 2019</title><link href="/france-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony Locke</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-07-13:/france-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Staying in a medieval town, there is plenty of inspiration for sketches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Arch" src="/images/2019/arch.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rose" src="/images/2019/rose.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our village there's an automated farm shop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cabane 4 Saisons" src="/images/2019/cabane.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You find the food you want by looking in the glass-fronted cabinets. Each
cabinet has a number, and when you punch in the number and pay, the cabinet
pings open …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Staying in a medieval town, there is plenty of inspiration for sketches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Arch" src="/images/2019/arch.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rose" src="/images/2019/rose.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our village there's an automated farm shop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cabane 4 Saisons" src="/images/2019/cabane.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You find the food you want by looking in the glass-fronted cabinets. Each
cabinet has a number, and when you punch in the number and pay, the cabinet
pings open. A bit like those Amazon lockers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought this dog-fouling notice was rather graphic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dog Fouling" src="/images/2019/dog.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've finished
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Under_the_Net"&gt;Iris Murdoch's Under The Net&lt;/a&gt;,
which I found hugely enjoyable. Here's a quote from it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain things I have learnt here: for instance, that my happiness wears a
sad face, so sad that for years I took it for my unhappiness and drove it
away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now fiddling around with Rust, making a battleships game.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>