<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tony Locke - Emily</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.tlocke.org.uk/feeds/emily.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2007-10-12T19:31:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>There's no current selection pressure to become 'g...</title><link href="/post-183112700264872389.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-10-12T19:31:00+01:00</published><updated>2007-10-12T19:31:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Emily</name></author><id>tag:None,2007-10-12:/post-183112700264872389.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's no current selection pressure to become 'grey goo'; a virus has no method of replicating itself other than hijacking other cells functions, and then having a mechanism to pass to another host. Viruses are also quite fragile in the environment, most need some sort of fluid transfer between hosts …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There's no current selection pressure to become 'grey goo'; a virus has no method of replicating itself other than hijacking other cells functions, and then having a mechanism to pass to another host. Viruses are also quite fragile in the environment, most need some sort of fluid transfer between hosts to propogate as they are vulnerable to heat and UV.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good virus has a symbiotic/parasitic relationship with it's host, the best are highjacked into junk DNA, and don't even have to bother replicating themselves as we pass the sequences to our offspring. Viruses are also fairly specific in what they can target (cell receptors), and if a virus was that aggressive the target hosts would combat with some sort of defence or go extinct.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a view that viruses ultimately drive/have driven evolution in a more critical manner than sexual reproduction.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Long answer: When people write Sci-fi they tend to...</title><link href="/post-3803683674165156020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-10-12T18:48:00+01:00</published><updated>2007-10-12T18:48:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Emily</name></author><id>tag:None,2007-10-12:/post-3803683674165156020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Long answer: When people write Sci-fi they tend to write about what ifs, often reflecting hopes or more commonly fears in their current society. Would you have 1985 without the fear of communism, the I robot series with out fear of automation removing jobs. The genre has now become more …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Long answer: When people write Sci-fi they tend to write about what ifs, often reflecting hopes or more commonly fears in their current society. Would you have 1985 without the fear of communism, the I robot series with out fear of automation removing jobs. The genre has now become more popular so it is more difficult to pick up on generalisations, and people are worried about more things, but some suggestions are David Brin - exploring where genetics could go, with a twist of environmentalism, I've just read Julian May's Rampant worlds - fear of capitalism without any control. I've read a lot of books that have a small band of people going off and settling a new colony Mayflower style with it's own particular quirk of religion/sociology/ideaology and then how that society copes/conflicts with a central authority when it is later integrated, surely based on changes due to increased migration or maybe just the fear of the unknown.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short answer: people don't write about what works well now as it'd be boring&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>