<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tony Locke - Miguel</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.tlocke.org.uk/feeds/miguel.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2008-01-31T11:06:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>FITs are by far the best solution we have for swit...</title><link href="/post-6143460658056989278.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-01-31T11:06:00+00:00</published><updated>2008-01-31T11:06:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Miguel</name></author><id>tag:None,2008-01-31:/post-6143460658056989278.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;FITs are by far the best solution we have for switching to a clean energy system. Having researched this for two years I have found that, every study, every expert, shows this. A carbon tax is not going to happen soon enough to make a difference in the short term …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;FITs are by far the best solution we have for switching to a clean energy system. Having researched this for two years I have found that, every study, every expert, shows this. A carbon tax is not going to happen soon enough to make a difference in the short term. Redirecting investment flows and changing the economics of true renewables is paramount - as is the parallel and complimentary strategy of energy efficiency, throughout our human activities.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It subsidizes THE solution, not 'a' solution. Nuclear - even if it was a benign technology - could not be built fast enough, at low enough cost to make an impact.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may well be the job of government to increase emissions costs - but no government is capable of doing this unilaterally, and there are zero indications that this will be done at supranational level.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feed-in tariffs engage citizens, businesses, community groups, farmers and corporates in taking action on climate change - both immediately, and with clear long-term consequences. FITs are a solution for now, and should be supported wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>