<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tony Locke - Tony</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.tlocke.org.uk/feeds/tony.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-04-21T16:12:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Bath Clean Air Zone</title><link href="/bath-clean-air-zone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-21T16:12:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T16:12:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-21:/bath-clean-air-zone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;BANES is to be congratulated for creating &lt;a href="http://www.bathnes.gov.uk/bath-breathes-2021"&gt;a plan to tackle the air pollution&lt;/a&gt; that is generated by transport in Bath. Unfortunately the plan has several flaws:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't consider pollution from brake and tyre dust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It considers pollution per vehicle rather than pollution per person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't help tackle …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;BANES is to be congratulated for creating &lt;a href="http://www.bathnes.gov.uk/bath-breathes-2021"&gt;a plan to tackle the air pollution&lt;/a&gt; that is generated by transport in Bath. Unfortunately the plan has several flaws:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't consider pollution from brake and tyre dust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It considers pollution per vehicle rather than pollution per person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn't help tackle congestion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is biased towards wealthy car users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cars generate more pollution per person than buses. Cars also impede the progress of buses within the city, making buses expensive, slow and unreliable. The key therefore is to reduce the number of cars in the city, thus improving air quality and making it easier for people to travel in the city using buses. How can this be achieved?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution is to turn all parking in the city into &lt;a href="https://bathnewseum.com/2017/12/04/the-end-of-free-parking-a-bonus-for-bnes-congestion-and-pollution/"&gt;residents' parking zones&lt;/a&gt;, where each resident has a reserved space in their local zone, but all other spaces have to be purchased at a higher price. Thus residents' parking zones reduce the number of cars on the road, making it cheaper and easier to use buses, and reducing air pollution from exhaust, brakes and tyres.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some may argue that even if buses aren't impeded by cars, the fares won't be reduced and the company will pocket the extra profit. If this happens, then BANES should use a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/quality-contract-scheme-board-announces-deadline-for-oral-evidence-requests"&gt;Quality Contract Scheme&lt;/a&gt; to punish anti-competitive behaviour by bus operators.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bus operators have adopted electronic ticketing in BANES where you activate your ticket on the phone just before boarding, and show the screen to the driver as you walk past. This is a great step forward, but the problem is that you have to buy a separate batch of tickets for each bus operator. BANES need to step in here and require that the same tickets work for any bus company.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With people travelling by bus rather than car, an immediate improvement is made to transport in Bath. However, we shouldn't stop there! Trams are superior to buses in that they pollute less, are cheaper to operate, have a higher capacity and are more pleasant to travel in. With the money generated from the parking zones, BANES should begin to build a &lt;a href="https://bathtrams.uk/"&gt;Bath tram network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Increasingly concerned about Facebook, Google etc</title><link href="/increasingly-concerned-about-facebook.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-17T22:12:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-17T22:12:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-17:/increasingly-concerned-about-facebook.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For some time I've been concerned about Google, Facebook etc. I'm writing this to try and pin down what my concerns are and what (if anything) I should do about it. So here are some thoughts in no particular order (a 'brain dump' in the vernacular):  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Monopoly&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For some time I've been concerned about Google, Facebook etc. I'm writing this to try and pin down what my concerns are and what (if anything) I should do about it. So here are some thoughts in no particular order (a 'brain dump' in the vernacular):  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Monopoly&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that with Facebook there's a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_effect"&gt;network effect&lt;/a&gt;, where the value of being part of a network increases with its size. So with Facebook, if 'everybody is on Facebook' then that's the one I'll join because I'll be able to communicate with everyone else. Conversely, leaving Facebook and trying to persuade people to use &lt;a href="https://www.signal.org/"&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; is difficult. I've tried and people just don't want to move  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Open Source&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be part of the solution. I'd call it a necessary, but not sufficient condition. With proprietary software you can't see what the software is doing, which is troubling to me. With open source software, people with the skill to read the code can raise the alarm if it's doing anything underhand.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Internet Freedom&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps part of what I'm concerned about could be called 'freedom on the internet'. Freedom from billionaires paying money to internet monopolies to influence me in an underhand way.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Walled Gardens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closed_platform"&gt;Walled gardens&lt;/a&gt; are part of the problem. Avoid them!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Advertising&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose it's not so much advertising, it's the diabolically clever targeting of it. For example, &lt;a href="https://duckduckgo.com/"&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt; has advertising, but it doesn't track you, and so there's none of that collection of personal data which is then used to manipulate you. Perhaps I'm saying that anything that allows micro-targeting is bad. So that would include any necessary steps (collecting personal data, organizing it in order to target people, and the actual adverts itself).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So those are, briefly, some of the problems. Here are some tentative solutions:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Open Source on mobile phone&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already use an open source operating system on my laptop, but my mobile phone runs stock Android. Really I should follow the steps that the FSFE gives to &lt;a href="https://fsfe.org/campaigns/android/liberate.en.html"&gt;Liberate Your Device&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Move away from Google&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is difficult. One thing I can do is move this blog and my website to be a simple static site, hosted without charge. The other thing is to review my various applications hosted on Google AppEngine and see what can be done about those.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;IPFS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ipfs.io/"&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt; is an alternative to the web, but still uses the internet. I should start to get to know it, and perhaps write an app. This won't solve things immediately, but it (or something like it) is needed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that's enough for now. I'll try and make a bit of progress and then come back and see what more I can do.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>How many flips of a coin before I get 7 heads in a row?</title><link href="/how-many-flips-of-coin-before-i-get-7.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-07T20:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-07T20:01:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-04-07:/how-many-flips-of-coin-before-i-get-7.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bill asked, 'On average, how many flips of a coin do I have to do to get 7 heads in a row?'. I thought this would be really easy, but I had to think about it for ages. I think it means, how many flips to get 50% probability of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bill asked, 'On average, how many flips of a coin do I have to do to get 7 heads in a row?'. I thought this would be really easy, but I had to think about it for ages. I think it means, how many flips to get 50% probability of getting 7 heads in a row. On Maths StackExchange there was &lt;a href="https://math.stackexchange.com/a/602194/195992"&gt;an answer&lt;/a&gt; that I didn't fully understand, but it said to do 1 - (probability of not getting 7 in a row). It also said to think about 'atoms' which for 7 heads are:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T&lt;br&gt;
HT&lt;br&gt;
HHT&lt;br&gt;
HHHT&lt;br&gt;
HHHHT&lt;br&gt;
HHHHHT&lt;br&gt;
HHHHHHT  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that the number of ways of not getting 7 heads in a row if you flip the coin 40 times, is the number of ways of arranging the atoms so that the total length is 41. I tried it out with smaller numbers first, so I thought about the chances of getting 2 heads in a row for 2 coin tosses. So in this case the atoms are:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T&lt;br&gt;
HT  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and the ways of arranging them in a total length of 3 are:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TTT&lt;br&gt;
THT&lt;br&gt;
HTT  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are 3 of them, and the total number of combinations are 2\^2 = 4, giving a probability of not getting two heads in a row of 3/4, and so the probability of getting two heads in a row is 1 - 3/4 = 1/4. Which we know is correct. So the problem now is, how do we work out the number of ways of arranging the atoms for 2 heads in an arbitrary length?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture below shows how I imagine it:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Diagram" src="/images/2018/2_heads.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting at zero, the single arrows mean an atom of length 1 (ie. a tail), and a double arrow means an atom of length 2 (ie. a head followed by a tail). The number of ways of getting to a certain length, is equal to the number of different paths to get to the number on the graph in the picture (that's what the number in brackets is). So for example, there are two ways to get to length 2, one way is to go from zero directly, and the other way is go via 1. Looking at the number of ways as the path length increases you get a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fibonacci_number"&gt;fibonacci sequence&lt;/a&gt;:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, ...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if there are n coin tosses the probability of getting two heads in a row is:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 - fib(n + 1) / 2\^n  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there we have it for 2 heads in a row, but what about 3? I drew another diagram, but with 3 arrows coming from each length rather than 2, and the number of ways of not getting 3 heads in a row was a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generalizations_of_Fibonacci_numbers#Fibonacci_numbers_of_higher_order"&gt;tribonacci&lt;/a&gt; sequence. The next term of the fibonacci sequence if found by adding up the two previous terms, but the next term in the tribonacci sequence is found by adding up the three previous terms. So it goes:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0, 0, 1, 1, 2, 4, 7, 13, 24, 44, 81, ...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say the nth term of a kth order fibonacci sequence is fib(k, n), then the probability of getting k heads in n flips is:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 - fib(k, n) / 2\^n  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's probably some fancy way of working this out, but I wrote a Python 3.6 programme to do it:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;prob = 0
NUM_IN_A_ROW = 7

while prob &amp;lt; 0.5:
    first_key, first_val = sorted(stream.items())[0]
    for v in range(NUM_IN_A_ROW):
        stream[first_key + v + 1] += first_val
    prob = 1 - stream[first_key + 1] / 2 ** first_key
    print(
        &amp;quot;After &amp;quot; + str(first_key) + &amp;quot; flips the probability of getting &amp;quot; +
        str(NUM_IN_A_ROW) + &amp;quot; in a row is &amp;quot; + str(prob))
    del stream[first_key]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Running this gives: &lt;code&gt;After 178 flips the probability of getting 7 in a row is 0.5014494277755364&lt;/code&gt;. So my answer is 178!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any corrections and comments welcome :-)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Update 2018-04-08&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having thought about the maths again, I think the Python can be written in a better way, and the &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/collections.html#collections.deque"&gt;deque&lt;/a&gt; data structure is well suited to finding n-order fibonacci sequences. So here's my second attempt, and reassuringly it comes out with the same answer.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;collections&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;deque&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;itertools&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class="n"&gt;NUM_IN_A_ROW&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;fibs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;deque&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;NUM_IN_A_ROW&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;tot&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;fib&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;fibs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;fibs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;fib&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;prob&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;fib&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tot&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;After {n} flips the probability of getting {NUM_IN_A_ROW} in a row &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;is {prob}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;prob&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;0.5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;tot&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Art therapy II</title><link href="/art-therapy-ii.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-07T11:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-07T11:55:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-03-07:/art-therapy-ii.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;7th March 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't as good a drawing as the last one, but the point of doing this isn't to create good pictures, it's to open up a dialogue with the unconscious. Sounds pretentious :-)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chocolate" src="/images/2018/chocolate.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a drawing of a dream I had recently, where we were &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galley_slave"&gt;galley slaves …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;7th March 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't as good a drawing as the last one, but the point of doing this isn't to create good pictures, it's to open up a dialogue with the unconscious. Sounds pretentious :-)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chocolate" src="/images/2018/chocolate.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a drawing of a dream I had recently, where we were &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galley_slave"&gt;galley slaves&lt;/a&gt;, and the gangmaster handed out a chocolate bar to every other person. The idea was that you gave half to the person behind you, and so everyone got half a bar of chocolate. I suddenly panicked that the person behind the person behind me might not have got any chocolate, and so I was ready to break my bar into thirds. She reassured me that she had received a bar herself and that the system was working, and so I was relieved.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The person on the left is me, then the man in the foreground on the right is the person I'm giving my half of the bar to, and the other person is the woman who was also given a bar.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8th March 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No images arose from my subconscious, so I decided to try and improve my drawing abilities by drawing from life a glass stopper of a bottle. I thought it would be really difficult, but it turned out to be way harder than that. The closer I looked, the more there was to see. I tried to draw everything I could see, but it was a herculean task, and it didn't look much like the actual stopper.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Stopper" src="/images/2018/stopper.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I got fed up and stopped half way through. You could say I was a stopper! (hehe).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;9th March 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, my subconscious isn't saying anything to me. Perhaps it's sulking? So I tried to draw the stopper again. The keen eyed will notice that it's not exactly the same stopper, because this one has '12' on it, but the other one had '22', but it's the same design.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Stopper 2" src="/images/2018/stopper2.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing with a biro is unforgiving for these two reasons: 1.) nothing can be undone,  2.) it's difficult to do flat areas of shade, it just looks like lines. Reflected light is best represented as a splodge of white on top of what's already there. You can't do that with biro because that splodge of light is the area that you have to leave completely alone. Since it's always additive, any biro drawing will get darker and darker as time goes on. The only way of making a patch seem lighter is to draw everything else on the page darker. Really difficult not to end up with a completely black page. The thing that prevents this is that it takes ages to colour in a page black with biro so most people give up before getting to the completely black stage. If, as Enoch Powell said, 'all political lives end in failure', then all biro drawings end in failure. That's why my stopper looks like a milk bottle top that needs a good clean.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;11th March 2018&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Neptune" src="/images/2018/IMG_20180311_194448614.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Art Therapy</title><link href="/art-therapy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-06T11:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-06T11:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-03-06:/art-therapy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I wrote in my last post, one of my tactics for recovering from burnout is art therapy. Here's my first effort:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="House" src="/images/2018/1520335228689919426944.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was inspired by watching a TV program about houses. I'm attracted to the idea of a post apocalyptic world, where people survive in a concrete bunker in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I wrote in my last post, one of my tactics for recovering from burnout is art therapy. Here's my first effort:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="House" src="/images/2018/1520335228689919426944.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was inspired by watching a TV program about houses. I'm attracted to the idea of a post apocalyptic world, where people survive in a concrete bunker in the forest. I'm struck by that story of people building wooden huts within the great stone walls left after the collapse of the Roman empire. They thought the stone ruins had been left by gods.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Burnout</title><link href="/burnout.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-02T15:34:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-02T15:34:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-03-02:/burnout.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It sounds like the title of a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dick_Francis"&gt;Dick Francis&lt;/a&gt; novel: Bonecrack, Knockdown, Smokescreen, Longshot. Burnout would fit right in.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Monday just gone I came to work and announced I was suffering from &lt;a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/basics/burnout"&gt;burnout&lt;/a&gt; and asked for some time off. It didn't come on suddenly, it crept up on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It sounds like the title of a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dick_Francis"&gt;Dick Francis&lt;/a&gt; novel: Bonecrack, Knockdown, Smokescreen, Longshot. Burnout would fit right in.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Monday just gone I came to work and announced I was suffering from &lt;a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/basics/burnout"&gt;burnout&lt;/a&gt; and asked for some time off. It didn't come on suddenly, it crept up on me, like the lobster in water of steadily increasing temperature. For me the symptom was a kind of slowing down of my work rate. Here's a graph, where the line in yellow is how things should be, and the line in red is how they were actually going:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Productivity" src="/images/2018/productivity.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly I didn't feel that the quality of my work had decreased, it was just taking more and more of an effort to focus.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my boss was excellent, and agreed that I should take some time off. I went to see the doctor, and she was really good too, pointing me in the direction of counselling, which I'm taking up.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things that I should mention: I like my job, it's not stressful, I'm doing the things I'd like to be doing and I work in an excellent team. On paper, things should be going swimmingly. My brain had other ideas though. Perhaps this is a case that shows that emotion always wins over thought.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's an example of a &lt;a href="http://carl-jung.net/mandala.html"&gt;mandala&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Jung"&gt;Jung&lt;/a&gt; saw as symbolizing the self:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/14/Mandala_gross.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mandala" height="320" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/14/Mandala_gross.jpg" width="224"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I've been drawn to Jung ever since I was a teenager. I've been reading him during this time off too. In contrast to my namesake &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Locke"&gt;John Locke&lt;/a&gt; who was an advocate of the 'blank slate' theory of human development, Jung thought that the brain already had encoded in it modules (called archetypes) for dealing with common elements of life. Here are some &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jungian_archetypes"&gt;archetypes&lt;/a&gt;:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birth, death, separation from parents, initiation, marriage, the union of opposites, great mother, father, child, devil, god, wise old man, wise old woman, the trickster, the hero,the apocalypse, the deluge and the creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that if you already had some things programmed in, this would give you an evolutionary advantage over your competitors. So where am I going with this? I'm not too sure, if I knew I'd be cured by now, but bear with me. According to Jung, the ego is the conscious part of the psyche, and it is in constant communication with the self, that has access to unconscious stored wisdom (archetypes and whatnot). The psyche is capable of regaining its equilibrium, involving the ego reconnecting with the self. That's my path to getting better.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The self communicates with the ego via feelings and dreams. My project while off work is to listen to my subconscious by:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing down my thoughts and feelings each day in a journal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking note of my dreams (only had one so far, rubbish!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditating and observing my thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being open to thoughts and feelings in day-to-day life, without censoring them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drawing things that might express an internal state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Counselling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's quite difficult, and I realize it sounds that I'm obsessed with myself. I am! I've worked out that the things that are preventing me from listening to my subconscious are:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on my many open source projects and ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drinking alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But aren't you bored, and also boring? Yes, but this is part of &lt;a href="http://www.jungny.com/lexicon.jungian.therapy.analysis/carl.jung.171.html"&gt;resistance&lt;/a&gt;. There's a big danger in defeating the repression of unconscious content though, as Jung writes:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one can never be too sure that the weak state of the patient's conscious mind will prove equal to the subsequent assault of the unconscious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I haven't abandoned TV altogether and I'm staying in touch with my friends, and making sure I get enough sleep and eat well. I'm also reading books which are nothing to do with psychoanalysis. I like chic-lit and SAS type books (which I believe are termed dick-lit).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.booktopia.com.au/http_coversbooktopiacomau/big/9780008155315/death-on-gibraltar-sas-operation-.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="SAS" height="320" src="http://www.booktopia.com.au/http_coversbooktopiacomau/big/9780008155315/death-on-gibraltar-sas-operation-.jpg" width="208"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I must get back to Joanna Trollope:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/513UDQMWsdL._SL300_.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Joanna Trollope" src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/513UDQMWsdL._SL300_.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Car Free Bath</title><link href="/car-free-bath.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-15T20:35:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-15T20:35:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-10-15:/car-free-bath.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Walking along &lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=18/51.37439/-2.37167"&gt;Oldfield Road&lt;/a&gt; on my way to work, I saw a notice attached to a lamppost. It turned out to be a traffic notice restricting parking in Oldfield Park, order &lt;a href="http://www.bathnes.gov.uk/services/streets-and-highway-maintenance/highway-improvements-traffic-management/traffic-regulatio-9"&gt;17-012/LC&lt;/a&gt;. The council were inviting comments, so I wrote the following in support of the order:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Walking along &lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=18/51.37439/-2.37167"&gt;Oldfield Road&lt;/a&gt; on my way to work, I saw a notice attached to a lamppost. It turned out to be a traffic notice restricting parking in Oldfield Park, order &lt;a href="http://www.bathnes.gov.uk/services/streets-and-highway-maintenance/highway-improvements-traffic-management/traffic-regulatio-9"&gt;17-012/LC&lt;/a&gt;. The council were inviting comments, so I wrote the following in support of the order:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a resident of Oldfield Park, I'm writing in support of the above&lt;br&gt;
scheme as I believe that removing parking is a necessary first step&lt;br&gt;
towards a car-free city. Cars cause traffic congestion and pollution&lt;br&gt;
and are dangerous. Removing parking will deter car use, and at the&lt;br&gt;
same time make routes more navigable for buses. Faster bus journeys&lt;br&gt;
will make buses cheaper and more frequent, setting up a virtuous&lt;br&gt;
circle. I note that the city of Oslo started their car-free program by&lt;br&gt;
first reducing parking, and are on track to be car-free by 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard people say, 'if buses were cheaper and more frequent then I'd use them, but until then I'll keep using my car'. The problem is that cars impede buses, which makes them more expensive and infrequent, so cars have to be removed first in order for buses to flourish.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason that everyone can't travel by car without causing traffic congestion is the large amount of space taken up by cars. Buses however take up far less space. This poster shows the space taken up by cars versus buses versus bicycles:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Capacity" src="/images/2017/picoftheday0012-space-60people.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the absence of cars is a necessary but not sufficient condition for buses to flourish. There has to be competition amongst the bus operators and electronic tickets that work with any bus operator.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>France 2017</title><link href="/france-2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-24T20:25:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-24T20:25:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-24:/france-2017.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the anti-penultimate day of the holiday in France, and I'm thinking back to our arrival. La Garde is about 30 minutes drive from Angers, so I hailed a taxi outside the station and we were off! The driver didn't recognize the address, but no matter, I directed him …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the anti-penultimate day of the holiday in France, and I'm thinking back to our arrival. La Garde is about 30 minutes drive from Angers, so I hailed a taxi outside the station and we were off! The driver didn't recognize the address, but no matter, I directed him from Google maps. We arrived, he dropped us off and drove away and I looked around for the gite. It was 22:00, and with mounting panic I realized we were in the wrong place. I told Claire not to panic, not realizing that it was I that was panicking, and that she was perfectly calm. Jung would have called it projection. There followed a period of confusion. I phoned for another taxi but my French was so bad that I was unsure whether I'd successfully done so. We waited for ages, but of course the taxi turned up and we made it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sunflowers" src="/images/2017/IMG_20170713_091121.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first book I read was &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Hero_of_Our_Time"&gt;A Hero of Our Time&lt;/a&gt;, with a Byronic anti-hero (the title is sardonic I think). On the other hand, he wasn't that bad. It's probably that in the time it was written it stood in contrast to the idealised characters that had always been portrayed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Countryside" src="/images/2017/IMG_20170716_091540348.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days into the holiday and we were walking from La Garde to Coutures by a roundabout route and we used a track that wasn't on Openstreetmap. &lt;a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=17/47.35453/-0.35798"&gt;It is now&lt;/a&gt;. I hadn't used Openstreetmap for ages, and was pleasantly surprised at how the editor had improved.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Map" src="/images/2017/map.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for my trip to France was to take a photo of the electricity meter at Château de Montsabert for Giles at work.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/56/Chateau_de_Montsabert_-_Petit.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Chateau de Montsabert" height="227" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/56/Chateau_de_Montsabert_-_Petit.jpg" width="320"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  Château de Montsabert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Electricity Meter" src="/images/2017/IMG_20170720_171522544.jpg"&gt;
  Electricity Meter at Montsabert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a fan of the &lt;a href="http://amzn.github.io/ion-docs/"&gt;Ion data serialization format&lt;/a&gt;, and for various reasons I wanted to write a parser for it. So I started working on it while in France, and I finished it yesterday. It's called &lt;a href="https://github.com/tlocke/pionic"&gt;Pionic&lt;/a&gt;. Ion is like JSON, but has support for timestamp and decimal data types, and more besides.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've just finished reading Jung's Modern Man in Search of a Soul, and he talks a lot about dreams, and how they are a way to access the unconscious mind. I don't really have dreams, but after starting to read the book I frequently had dreams. In my latest dream I was the science advisor to President Barack Obama and I was terrified that he'd ask me what the atomic number of nitrogen was, and I wouldn't be able to tell him confidently.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title></title><link href="/yesterday-i-went-out-canvassing-for.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-09T09:21:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-05-09T09:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-05-09:/yesterday-i-went-out-canvassing-for.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I went out canvassing for &lt;a href="http://werahobhouse.wordpress.com/"&gt;Wera Hobhouse&lt;/a&gt; of the Lib Dems, who is standing for Bath MP. I haven't been canvassing since I went round with my Dad many years ago, when he was a town councillor.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm just about to go out again this morning, traveling up to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I went out canvassing for &lt;a href="http://werahobhouse.wordpress.com/"&gt;Wera Hobhouse&lt;/a&gt; of the Lib Dems, who is standing for Bath MP. I haven't been canvassing since I went round with my Dad many years ago, when he was a town councillor.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm just about to go out again this morning, traveling up to Odd Down. Must make sure I get a rosette this time.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>I've Joined The Liberal Democrats</title><link href="/ive-joined-liberal-democrats.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-18T19:56:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-18T19:56:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-04-18:/ive-joined-liberal-democrats.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2017/apr/18/theresa-may-uk-general-election-8-june"&gt;snap election announcement&lt;/a&gt;, I've joined the Liberal Democrats as I believe they're our best chance of stopping Brexit.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking over their website, they say that they're against a hard Brexit, rather than simply against Brexit. But this is better than the Tories, and in my &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bath_(UK_Parliament_constituency)#Elections_in_the_2010s"&gt;constituency of Bath …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2017/apr/18/theresa-may-uk-general-election-8-june"&gt;snap election announcement&lt;/a&gt;, I've joined the Liberal Democrats as I believe they're our best chance of stopping Brexit.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking over their website, they say that they're against a hard Brexit, rather than simply against Brexit. But this is better than the Tories, and in my &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bath_(UK_Parliament_constituency)#Elections_in_the_2010s"&gt;constituency of Bath&lt;/a&gt; the 2015 general election results were:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conservative 17,833&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liberal Democrat 14,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Labour 6,216&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green 5,634&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UKIP 2,922&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent 499&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;English Democrat 63 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My MP, Ben Howlett (Conservative), &lt;a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/mp/25334/ben_howlett/bath/divisions?policy=6761"&gt;voted with his party to trigger Article 50&lt;/a&gt;, but the Lib Dem position was to &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2017/mar/14/parliament-article-50-lib-dems-opposition-brexit"&gt;vote against Article 50&lt;/a&gt;. So I reasoned that the best hope to get a pro-EU MP for Bath is to do what I can to help the Lib Dems, so I've stumped up £70 and &lt;a href="http://www.libdems.org.uk/"&gt;joined them&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People argue that the referendum result was the will of the people and parliament must comply with it. I feel that in this tussle between the referendum and parliament, ultimately parliament should decide. Referendums are never a good idea, and I was against a referendum right from the beginning.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone's still reading, here's my main reason for wanting to be part of the EU. We've got to have some way of coexisting with other people, and democracy seems the least bad approach. Without the EU we'd have democracy up to the national level, but anarchy beyond that. As we know, in an anarchy, life is 'solitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short'. Without an EU we've had two world wars; essentially European civil wars played out over the globe. On the other hand, with the EU we'd have democracy right up to the continental level, which is our best chance of peace.  &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Louis XV</title><link href="/louis-xv.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-10T19:19:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-10T19:19:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-06-10:/louis-xv.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chair" src="/images/2016/IMG_20160610_182727009.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my Louis XV chair, which with &lt;em&gt;folies de grandeure&lt;/em&gt; I think of as my 'reading chair'. It's right below the window where the resident smokes his Galois and looks out at the Loire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to &lt;a href="http://m.lasourisgourmande.com/"&gt;La Souris Gourmande&lt;/a&gt; for lunch, and a fellow diner was a famous …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chair" src="/images/2016/IMG_20160610_182727009.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my Louis XV chair, which with &lt;em&gt;folies de grandeure&lt;/em&gt; I think of as my 'reading chair'. It's right below the window where the resident smokes his Galois and looks out at the Loire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to &lt;a href="http://m.lasourisgourmande.com/"&gt;La Souris Gourmande&lt;/a&gt; for lunch, and a fellow diner was a famous person. I didn't recognise him myself, but people came up to him and asked for selfies. All I can say is that he wore immaculately white trainers, and that he ate fondue with two friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You distracted me there, but in that chair I was reading C. P. Snow's The Sleep Of Reason. I think he may be one of my favourite authors. There's a bit where he says that free will may not exist, but you have to go in as though it did. It's not a very satisfactory answer to the problem, but it's the same (provisional) conclusion I've come to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well the task for me now is to find a suitable bar to watch France v. Romania in the opening game of Euro 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Mon Ami Jaeger</title><link href="/mon-ami-jaeger.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-08T16:38:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-08T16:38:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-06-08:/mon-ami-jaeger.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Jaeger" src="/images/2016/IMG_20160608_141441.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's allowed on the chairs at the café!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Jaeger" src="/images/2016/IMG_20160608_141441.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's allowed on the chairs at the café!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Hello Again Jaeger</title><link href="/hello-again-jaeger.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-08T13:58:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-08T13:58:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-06-08:/hello-again-jaeger.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Through a great green front door, thick with decades of layers of paint. Up ancient, rickety, Dickensian stairs in the gloom, each step yielding a creak. Then into the apartment looking out onto the Loire in the dazzling sun.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've renewed my friendship with the black Labrador called Jaeger at …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Through a great green front door, thick with decades of layers of paint. Up ancient, rickety, Dickensian stairs in the gloom, each step yielding a creak. Then into the apartment looking out onto the Loire in the dazzling sun.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've renewed my friendship with the black Labrador called Jaeger at Les Blancs Manteaux, and thereby came to an act of civic heroism. An elderly man walking a small dog was trying to hold back the Jaeger, but was too frail. I promptly grabbed Jaeger by the collar and the old man gratefully carried on his way. The people of the town have commissioned a statue in honor of my bravery.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Loire burst its banks in the deluge, and there are still parts of the riverside path that are inundated. Walking along, a woman on a bike stopped and asked if the way I had come was flooded. I replied that it wasn't flooded, and it was clear for her to keep cycling along. She didn't seem to grasp what I was saying, and so I became quite insistent that the way was clear. This went on for some time until she pointed behind her at a flood that I was about to encounter. It dawned on that she hadn't been asking me about her way ahead, she had been warning me about my way ahead. I laughed, but she did not.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I'm a hypochondriac, I'm convinced I've got a sleeping disorder.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Police Commissioner Elections</title><link href="/police-commissioner-elections.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-05T08:09:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-05-05T08:09:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-05-05:/police-commissioner-elections.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just remembered to vote in the &lt;a href="https://www.choosemypcc.org.uk/area/avon-somerset"&gt;Police Commissioner elections&lt;/a&gt;. My area is Avon and Somerset and my vote was:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerry Barker (Labour)&lt;br&gt;
Chris Briton (Green)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I voted Barker because of his policy of helmet mounted cameras, and Briton for his drug decriminalisation stance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just remembered to vote in the &lt;a href="https://www.choosemypcc.org.uk/area/avon-somerset"&gt;Police Commissioner elections&lt;/a&gt;. My area is Avon and Somerset and my vote was:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerry Barker (Labour)&lt;br&gt;
Chris Briton (Green)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I voted Barker because of his policy of helmet mounted cameras, and Briton for his drug decriminalisation stance.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>UK Budget 2016</title><link href="/uk-budget-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-16T18:47:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-16T18:47:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-03-16:/uk-budget-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looking at the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-35819797"&gt;main points&lt;/a&gt; of the UK 2016 budget, I'm pleased that the Chancellor is cutting spending, but I'm not happy about where he's cutting it. Here are some comments on the specific items:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abolition of Class 2 National Insurance contributions.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Good.&lt;/strong&gt; National Insurance is a &lt;a href="http://neilharding.blogspot.co.uk/2014/07/national-insurance-it-regressive-nature.html"&gt;regressive tax&lt;/a&gt;, and …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looking at the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-35819797"&gt;main points&lt;/a&gt; of the UK 2016 budget, I'm pleased that the Chancellor is cutting spending, but I'm not happy about where he's cutting it. Here are some comments on the specific items:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abolition of Class 2 National Insurance contributions.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Good.&lt;/strong&gt; National Insurance is a &lt;a href="http://neilharding.blogspot.co.uk/2014/07/national-insurance-it-regressive-nature.html"&gt;regressive tax&lt;/a&gt;, and should be abolished entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The threshold at which people pay 40% income tax will rise from £42,385 to £45,000 in April 2017.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Bad.&lt;/strong&gt; If there's money to spare for tax cuts it should be used to cut the taxes of the poor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T&lt;em&gt;ax-free personal allowance to rise from £11,000 to £11,500.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Good.&lt;/strong&gt; This is cutting taxes for the poor, which tackles inequality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital Gains Tax to be cut.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Neither.&lt;/strong&gt; Capital Gains should be taxed at exactly the same rate as income.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Annual Isa limit to rise from £15,240 to £20,000.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Bad.&lt;/strong&gt; ISAs should be abolished. They're bureaucratic and the money should instead go to abolishing taxes on the poor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;New "lifetime" Isa for the under-40s.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Bad.&lt;/strong&gt; As above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;New state-backed savings scheme.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Bad.&lt;/strong&gt; As above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>An Anarchy Of Nations</title><link href="/an-anarchy-of-nations.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-05T16:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-05T16:05:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-03-05:/an-anarchy-of-nations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Walking through Green Park Station in Bath, a man from the Leave the EU campaign saw me and proffered a leaflet. I said that I was in favour of remaining in the EU. He asked why and I explained that at the European level we've got democracy at the moment …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Walking through Green Park Station in Bath, a man from the Leave the EU campaign saw me and proffered a leaflet. I said that I was in favour of remaining in the EU. He asked why and I explained that at the European level we've got democracy at the moment, but if we were to leave the EU we'd go back to having Europe as an anarchy of nations (two world wars etc). He said, 'well if you follow that logic we'd have a world government!', I said, 'yes we should have a world government', at which he recoiled and gave me up as a hopeless case.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Dear Ben Howlet, please vote against the bombing of Syria</title><link href="/dear-ben-howlet-please-vote-against.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-29T13:44:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-11-29T13:44:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-11-29:/dear-ben-howlet-please-vote-against.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's the letter I sent to my MP Ben Howlett:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Ben Howlett,  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing to urge you to vote against the bombing of Syria.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onus is on those making the case for military action to show that it will do more good than harm. In my view …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's the letter I sent to my MP Ben Howlett:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Ben Howlett,  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing to urge you to vote against the bombing of Syria.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onus is on those making the case for military action to show that it will do more good than harm. In my view they have not done this.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legality of bombing is also in question. In order to go ahead with the bombing there would need to be a security council resolution passed that would allow it. As far as I no there has been no such resolution.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do know that bombing raids will put the lives of our air crew at risk, and we do know that innocent civilians will die, no matter how careful we are. And for what? With the Russians supporting Assad, Turkey against the Kurds, Turkey and Russia in conflict with each other, Assad fighting everyone else in Syria including civilians, bombing by the USA and allies, the situation is so confused that it's impossible to be certain of the consequences of our actions.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead I advocate that the UK take two actions:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Continuing with the safe havens outside Syria that we're already funding.&lt;br&gt;
* Attempting to create an international strategy under the UN that would block all arms going into Syria, and also a financial blockade against ISIS.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a pacifist, and in the case of ISIS in Iraq we are right to continue military action as this is entirely legal and has the clear aim of restoring Iraq to the Iraqi government.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards,  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tony Locke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Will The Future Workplace Still Need You?</title><link href="/will-future-workplace-still-need-you_27.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-27T18:08:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-09-27T18:08:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-09-27:/will-future-workplace-still-need-you_27.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My friend Kazim Ladimeji has written a book called &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Will-Future-Workplace-Still-Need-ebook/dp/B0106CUM7C/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1443373773&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Will The Future Workplace Still Need You?&lt;/a&gt;, which I've just finished reading. As he says, this isn't a book of philosophical speculation, but a practical guide on what action the individual should take to avoid being replaced by a robot. The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My friend Kazim Ladimeji has written a book called &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Will-Future-Workplace-Still-Need-ebook/dp/B0106CUM7C/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1443373773&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Will The Future Workplace Still Need You?&lt;/a&gt;, which I've just finished reading. As he says, this isn't a book of philosophical speculation, but a practical guide on what action the individual should take to avoid being replaced by a robot. The time-scale goes from the present to about 20 years in the future.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that impressed me about this book was that it's based on a number of rigorous studies, and concrete examples are given that are properly referenced. In short, it's well researched.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazim tells us about jobs that have already been automated, and then those that will be automated in the near future. He also talks about jobs that have a low probability of being automated, and new jobs that don't exist yet. These new jobs include Nostalgist, Rewilder and Robot Counsellor. When I saw the title Robot Counsellor I thought it meant people that talked to robots that had problems. To find out what it actually means, you'll have to read the book!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Broken Laptop</title><link href="/broken-laptop.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-25T21:25:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-08-25T21:25:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-08-25:/broken-laptop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My laptop was under a beanbag and I trod on it and broke the screen:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Broken Laptop" src="/images/2015/1440534071914-2095135209.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've ordered one of &lt;a href="http://m.ebuyer.com/705954"&gt;these&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My laptop was under a beanbag and I trod on it and broke the screen:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Broken Laptop" src="/images/2015/1440534071914-2095135209.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've ordered one of &lt;a href="http://m.ebuyer.com/705954"&gt;these&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>France 2015: 6</title><link href="/france-2015-6.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-22T19:25:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-07-22T19:25:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-07-22:/france-2015-6.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a picture of a cat so that my blog becomes popular on the internet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cat" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150721_120631.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy now?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the cathedral just round the corner from me:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cathedral" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150718_205637.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bridge over the Loire at Tours that the trams and cars go over:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bridge" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150720_110937.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faded grandeur:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Grandeur" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150720_121839.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, there's more!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen frameborder="0" height="344" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h3on3pyNHOQ" width="459"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a picture of a cat so that my blog becomes popular on the internet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cat" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150721_120631.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy now?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the cathedral just round the corner from me:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cathedral" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150718_205637.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bridge over the Loire at Tours that the trams and cars go over:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bridge" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150720_110937.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faded grandeur:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Grandeur" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150720_121839.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, there's more!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen frameborder="0" height="344" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h3on3pyNHOQ" width="459"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>France 2015: 5</title><link href="/france-2015-5.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-16T18:51:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-07-16T18:51:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-07-16:/france-2015-5.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dave and Andy have asked me to take some photos of trains for their website. I protested that my camera's not very good and that I'm a rubbish photographer. Anyway, against my will here are some tram-related photos. There seems to be just one long track, stretching as far as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dave and Andy have asked me to take some photos of trains for their website. I protested that my camera's not very good and that I'm a rubbish photographer. Anyway, against my will here are some tram-related photos. There seems to be just one long track, stretching as far as the eye can see in either direction:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tram Tracks" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150714_115703.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says 15mins until the next tram. Not very frequent.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Next Tram" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150714_115830.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While walking over the bridge by the tram track, this graffito caught my eye:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="No Money" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150714_120306.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tram approaches a stop:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tram Arrives" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150714_120747.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eagle-eyed tram spotter will have spotted that while there are overhead wires on most bits, there aren't any on the bridge. It must have batteries or something.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Close-up of Tram" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150714_120804.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.aulapinquifume.fr/"&gt;Au Lapin qui Fume&lt;/a&gt; restaurant is excellent. Here's their signature entree, lapin terrine:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lapin Terrine" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150715_133440.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that this says: No Swimming, but what does the bit underneath say?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="No Swimming" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150716_121639.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il fait pleut. It's just a light rain, not cold, but it caught me unawares and I ducked into l'Indian Bar Cafe. Did I tell you that I like rain? Setting the scene, the usually bustling Rue Blanqui is all but deserted. I'm the only one sitting outside under the awning. A rubbish lorry came by and one of the guys waved a hearty bonjour, to which I replied enthusiastically. Of course, they had been waving at the cafe proprietor behind me. Awkward.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man in his sixties comes out to smoke. He has a phlegmatic mien. I remark, man to man, that it is raining. He doesn't understand. I try again and this time he understands what I've said, but not why I've said it. He goes back to his rollup, his weary view of humanity undisturbed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh God, Blue Shirt has arrived. Before I know it I've welcomed him to my table and bought him a coffee. Why, why, why??  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's not a popular man. If I carry on encouraging him I'll become unpopular too.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>France 2015: 4</title><link href="/france-2015-4.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-13T12:17:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-07-13T12:17:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-07-13:/france-2015-4.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pump" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_105653.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every morning we stand in a queue for water at the pump...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Balcony" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_105705.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Romeo and Juliette style balcony just outside my front door.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Church" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_111730.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, this photo was taken at the time I stepped in a huge dog turd.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Golden Sculpture" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_120051.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a monument built by Americans to thank the French …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pump" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_105653.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every morning we stand in a queue for water at the pump...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Balcony" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_105705.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Romeo and Juliette style balcony just outside my front door.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Church" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_111730.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, this photo was taken at the time I stepped in a huge dog turd.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Golden Sculpture" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_120051.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a monument built by Americans to thank the French for their help with supplies during the first world war. There's a marble statue labelled Procurement.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Loire" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_121847.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long walk by the Loire to get the dog poo off my shoe.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Beer" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150712_132419.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An accordion player just walked past. A bit awkward as I was sitting outside eating and couldn't avoid him. Things got worse as he homed in on me as a vulnerable tourist. He serenaded me and then I felt obliged to give him two Euros. Note to self: remain resolute when faced with buskers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Shirt had made a reappearance. He sprang to my side and shook hands like a long lost friend. He reminded me of the coffee I had promised to buy him, and I rashly said that we'd go to a bar and I would buy him a coffee. The owners of the bar were well acquainted with Blue Shirt, and expressed scepticism about his ability to pay. At that he gestured to me and announced, 'the English will pay!'. He made a nuisance of himself at the café, butting in to other people's conversations and generally being annoying. He kept asking me for money and I kept refusing. I made an excuse that I had to go back to the house, but in fact I'm studying Kyle Brooks' tutorial on logic on a nearby bench. I'm anxious about him finding me.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hamster" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150713_104454.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know what this place is. It's near me and you can see it says Murder Hamster on the door.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>France 2015: 3 - The Langford Kebab</title><link href="/france-2015-3-langford-kebab.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-11T19:44:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-07-11T19:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-07-11:/france-2015-3-langford-kebab.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My friend Andy challenged me to solve the &lt;a href="http://puzzling.stackexchange.com/questions/2038/8-dimensional-vegetable-kebab"&gt;Langford Kebab&lt;/a&gt; puzzle. I'm not clever enough to work it out, so I wrote a &lt;a href="https://github.com/tlocke/geocache/blob/master/langford/langford.py"&gt;computer program&lt;/a&gt; to work it out by brute force.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My friend Andy challenged me to solve the &lt;a href="http://puzzling.stackexchange.com/questions/2038/8-dimensional-vegetable-kebab"&gt;Langford Kebab&lt;/a&gt; puzzle. I'm not clever enough to work it out, so I wrote a &lt;a href="https://github.com/tlocke/geocache/blob/master/langford/langford.py"&gt;computer program&lt;/a&gt; to work it out by brute force.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>France 2015: 2</title><link href="/france-2015-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-11T16:05:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-07-11T16:05:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-07-11:/france-2015-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bought a big bottle of cognac because that's what they always drink in Balzac. I'm in Balzac country now. I don't even like cognac.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stopped off on the way back for a limonade. It's the same price as a pression. Talking of booze prices, the price of whisky is about …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bought a big bottle of cognac because that's what they always drink in Balzac. I'm in Balzac country now. I don't even like cognac.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stopped off on the way back for a limonade. It's the same price as a pression. Talking of booze prices, the price of whisky is about 2/3 of the price it is in the UK. Yet the UK has a bigger alcohol problem than France. Alcohol tax seems to be another way of taxing the poor.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished reading Simon, The Genius In My Basement, by Alex Masters. I find it reassuring to read about someone infinitely more odd than me. Simon Norton did have the consolation of being a genius. Although perhaps it's more accurate to say that he was a prodigy. The received wisdom in the maths community was that in about 1985 he lost his brilliant and became mad and troubled. According to the biography that isn't true. Norton is happy and still making mathematical contributions. It's true that he's odd, but then some people are, and nobody's bothered, least of all him.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cappucino was milder and creamier than we get in Bath. Beautifully presented with a carafe of water.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150711_113038.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're wondering why the photos look so bad, it's because I'm using the latest instagram filter for making it look like the camera's been damaged. BTW, that book on the right is Centuary Rain by Alasdair Reynolds. As the regular reader of this blog knows (hello Bill!) he's one of the greatest sci-fi authors alive and any book by him is a real treat.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="River" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150711_121817.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quick oil painting I did while standing with my easel on a bridge down river of this one.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Church" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150711_124118.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On crossing the river I sat down on a bench in the shade of some trees and took this photo. There was a water stand pipe just to the left of the picture. A child started to go near it, but his father stopped him with a remonstrative bark, afraid that it wasn't drinking water. A few minutes later the boy came back with his mother and they played around splashing the water everywhere.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Records" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150711_152316.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop me if I'm getting tedious, but I took this photo for Andy. It's on the Rue Blanqui, the same street that my house is on. Blanqui was a socialist who advocated armed rebellion and who said, 'he who has iron, has bread!'  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Church" src="/images/2015/IMG_20150711_154219.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the sort of thing you stumbe across down a side street in Tours.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a great deal of smoking here. Everyone smokes and drinks a great deal, lounging around in bars. I feel at home here.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having lunch outside (in fact I've *only* eaten outdoors at restaurants) I sat in the square. A guy in a blue shirt came up begging for money and I said I'd buy him some food. Blue Shirt really wanted money to buy it with, but I insisted on actually buying it. Then he said he wanted some money to buy coffee instead. So I went to the nearest coffee shop and bought some porte coffee. When I got back Blue Shirt had disappeared, so I went back to reading my book and started to drink the coffee myself.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, this story's going on a bit longer than I thought it would, bear with me.  So then this other guy, late fifties, smartly dressed in a white shirt came over and peered at me intently. I grinned nervously and he carried on a bit, then turned to me and said in English, 'are you English?', when I said I was he seemed pleased and got out a folder of papers and asked me to check a translation for the instructions for a Paris flat that he rented out.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assented, but when we were half-way through the translation the first guy, Blue Shirt turned up again and demanded some money. I explained to Blue Shirt what had happened with the coffee in broken English, while White Shirt looked on bemused. I asked Blue Shirt to wait for five minutes while I finished translating for White Shirt, but Blue Shirt started arguing and then stormed off. White Shirt commented drily that I seemed to have made friends in the town very quickly.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I go on to describe another incident with somone begging for money, you might get the impression that there are lots of homeless people in Tours. You shouldn't get that impression, it's just that we tend to attract each other. Anyway, a man hailed me from the pavement where he was sitting amongst his homeless friends (including a dog, which I was sad to see he didn't treat very well). He asked for money, and I asked him if a sandwich would do. I bought him a sandwich and he and his friends were grateful, and now I get a friendly wave whenever I walk past his gang.  &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>France 2015: 1</title><link href="/france-2015-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-07-10T15:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T15:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-07-10:/france-2015-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm feeling sad. Can't concentrate to read a book. It's a passing thing, and I'll feel silly at writing it later on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The awkward turtle has seen plenty of action. Knowing only a small amount of French seems to guarantee that I generate at least one profoundly awkward moment during …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm feeling sad. Can't concentrate to read a book. It's a passing thing, and I'll feel silly at writing it later on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The awkward turtle has seen plenty of action. Knowing only a small amount of French seems to guarantee that I generate at least one profoundly awkward moment during each conversation.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I arrived at the flat, the owner asked in French if I planned on visiting the local Châteaux. I confidently replied in French, 'no, it is me only'. She adopted a WTF expression.&lt;br&gt;
The thing is, I thought she had asked, 'will you be having any visitors to the house?'  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a thousand incidents like this, and many more to come.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I have ordered moules a la creme, a bier and a glass of water. Success!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>One Night In Bangkok - Myers-Briggs</title><link href="/one-night-in-bangkok-myers-briggs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-25T19:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-25T19:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-11-25:/one-night-in-bangkok-myers-briggs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm a fan of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P9mwELXPGbA&amp;amp;list=PLA679D813DB2C004D"&gt;Murray Head's One Night In Bangkok&lt;/a&gt;. As an aside a cherished memory I have is of travelling in the back seat of the car with my uncle driving, aunt in the passenger seat and brother next to me. We were listening to this song on the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm a fan of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P9mwELXPGbA&amp;amp;list=PLA679D813DB2C004D"&gt;Murray Head's One Night In Bangkok&lt;/a&gt;. As an aside a cherished memory I have is of travelling in the back seat of the car with my uncle driving, aunt in the passenger seat and brother next to me. We were listening to this song on the radio, in the early eighties. I just can't describe the feelings that accompany that memory.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the point of this post is that in the song there's an ongoing conversation between Murray Head and the chorus. I wondered what &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Myers-Briggs_Type_Indicator"&gt;Myers-Briggs&lt;/a&gt; types the two fell into. I'd put Head as a &lt;a href="https://www.personalitypage.com/ENTJ.html"&gt;ENTJ&lt;/a&gt;, and the chorus as &lt;a href="https://www.personalitypage.com/ESFJ.html"&gt;ESFJ&lt;/a&gt;. What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title></title><link href="/claire-sent-me-this-photo-of-loo-with.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-01T15:21:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-01T15:21:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-11-01:/claire-sent-me-this-photo-of-loo-with.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Loo" src="/images/2014/photo.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claire sent me this photo of a loo with a washbasin on top. I assume that the water from the basin fills the cistern. That's a brilliant idea.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Loo" src="/images/2014/photo.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claire sent me this photo of a loo with a washbasin on top. I assume that the water from the basin fills the cistern. That's a brilliant idea.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Hydrogen Sonata</title><link href="/the-hydrogen-sonata.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-23T15:02:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-23T15:02:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-10-23:/the-hydrogen-sonata.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Hydrogen Sonata was one of the books I picked up from the library to read on holiday. I read bits now and again, but didn't find myself engaged with it for some reason. Then, in the last quarter of the book I began to feel excited about it. It …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Hydrogen Sonata was one of the books I picked up from the library to read on holiday. I read bits now and again, but didn't find myself engaged with it for some reason. Then, in the last quarter of the book I began to feel excited about it. It stayed that way to the end.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it inevitable that as life becomes more technically advanced, society becomes more morally advanced? Even though humans have been unchanged in their abilities for about 10,000 years, our society has steadily improved morally as well as technically. Is this inevitable? Will this continue as AIs take over from humans?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My answer is yes. Democracy and the rule of law has improved things for people because it's a solution to the prisoners' dilemma. More advanced AIs will recognise this more clearly and so I hope the rule of law and democracy will continue.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>The Pregnant Widow</title><link href="/the-pregnant-widow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-22T13:18:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-22T13:18:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-10-22:/the-pregnant-widow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Initially the dialogue was clever, but it became relentlessly clever, and I said wearily, okay Martin, you win, you've more than proved yourself, now leave me in peace.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was okay because I found an antidote in the search for an explanation for prime numbers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back to the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Initially the dialogue was clever, but it became relentlessly clever, and I said wearily, okay Martin, you win, you've more than proved yourself, now leave me in peace.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was okay because I found an antidote in the search for an explanation for prime numbers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back to the Widow now and again, and I started to enjoy it more and more. There were tensions developing, and some of the clever things made sense, and I still laugh at the bit of the telegram that read, 'black bear repeat black bear'.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much like the end of the book where there are chapters for various years after main story, explaining what happened to the characters. More authors should do this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>The Music of the Primes</title><link href="/the-music-of-primes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-21T12:54:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-21T12:54:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-10-21:/the-music-of-primes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The most gripping book I've read so far on my two week holiday is Marcus du Sautoy's Music of the Primes. These types of books are destined to be described as a 'fascinating journey'. It was, how shall I put it? A fascinating journey through the drama and personalities of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The most gripping book I've read so far on my two week holiday is Marcus du Sautoy's Music of the Primes. These types of books are destined to be described as a 'fascinating journey'. It was, how shall I put it? A fascinating journey through the drama and personalities of the search for an explanation of prime numbers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the sad things about it all is that there's a belief among mathematicians that your mathematical abilities decline after you're 30. Kind of depressing. Having said that, Euler and Erdos  were apparently mathematically active to a ripe old age.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>The Bearded Mermaid</title><link href="/well-i-brought-whole-lot-of-books-to.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-16T20:02:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-16T20:02:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-10-16:/well-i-brought-whole-lot-of-books-to.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well I brought a whole lot of books to Charlestown. I've been haunting the cafés and restaurants carrying a copy of Anthony Trollope's Dr. Thorne. I always enjoy reading Trollope. I wonder if I can describe to you why?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy's a liberal, he has a liberal attitude. These days …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well I brought a whole lot of books to Charlestown. I've been haunting the cafés and restaurants carrying a copy of Anthony Trollope's Dr. Thorne. I always enjoy reading Trollope. I wonder if I can describe to you why?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy's a liberal, he has a liberal attitude. These days people would say he's not judgemental. Don't judge me dude!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, he gently points out the hypocrisies, inconsistencies and failings of his characters, but it's as if he's describing what it means to be human, rather than damning the individual he's talking about.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next book is a Martin Amis. I'll be sitting reading it on the rocks in the sea, like a bookish mermaid. With a beard.  &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>In Search Of Lost Vice</title><link href="/in-search-of-lost-vice.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-29T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-29T18:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-08-29:/in-search-of-lost-vice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_World_problem"&gt;First world problem&lt;/a&gt; alert!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the amazing things about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_Search_of_Lost_Time"&gt;In Search Of Lost Time&lt;/a&gt; is how many of Proust's observations of how the mind and memory work are now shown to be scientifically correct.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember in the mid-eighties watching Miami Vice as a child. Maybe eighty-five or …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_World_problem"&gt;First world problem&lt;/a&gt; alert!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the amazing things about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_Search_of_Lost_Time"&gt;In Search Of Lost Time&lt;/a&gt; is how many of Proust's observations of how the mind and memory work are now shown to be scientifically correct.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember in the mid-eighties watching Miami Vice as a child. Maybe eighty-five or eighty-six. That sounds quite old for a child? No, I'm talking about the year. Anyway, I used to watch that programme and now the memory of it is very potent. The &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GQDU-2qMre0"&gt;theme tune&lt;/a&gt; takes me back to those days in &lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/node/2858347220#map=19/51.28337/-1.99848"&gt;Littleton Panel&lt;/a&gt; when I'd stay up late on my own watching the TV.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I listen to it on Youtube, and I've now listened to it loads more times on Youtube than in the eighties. Am I, as Proust would have it, destroying my memory of that time? As, I understand the research, memories that are retrieved are put back and the putting back changes them, it is a creative process. Proust is right. I'm sad to be slowly losing that memory. Or maybe I'm wrong...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Various Maths Puzzles</title><link href="/various-maths-puzzles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-21T16:34:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-21T16:34:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-06-21:/various-maths-puzzles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've come across some good maths puzzles recently. I thought I'd list them so that I don't forget them.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Petersburg_paradox"&gt;St Petersburg Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mathoverflow.net/questions/17960/google-question-in-a-country-in-which-people-only-want-boys"&gt;Google interview question: Proportion of boys and girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wired.co.uk/magazine/google-answers"&gt;Google interview question: One shot or two out of three shots?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've come across some good maths puzzles recently. I thought I'd list them so that I don't forget them.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Petersburg_paradox"&gt;St Petersburg Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mathoverflow.net/questions/17960/google-question-in-a-country-in-which-people-only-want-boys"&gt;Google interview question: Proportion of boys and girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wired.co.uk/magazine/google-answers"&gt;Google interview question: One shot or two out of three shots?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Skip 2014-01-18 Feb and March</title><link href="/skip-2014-01-18.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-09T21:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-09T21:24:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-06-09:/skip-2014-01-18.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 1" src="/images/2014/IMG_20140118_151915.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 2" src="/images/2014/IMG_20140203_080857.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 3" src="/images/2014/IMG_20140329_161521.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 1" src="/images/2014/IMG_20140118_151915.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 2" src="/images/2014/IMG_20140203_080857.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 3" src="/images/2014/IMG_20140329_161521.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="skip-watch"></category></entry><entry><title>EU Elections Tomorrow</title><link href="/eu-elections-tomorrow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-21T22:09:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-05-21T22:09:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-05-21:/eu-elections-tomorrow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the EU elections on Thursday, I realize I've got to get my head round it all and decide who I'm voting for. The BANES website &lt;a href="http://www.bathnes.gov.uk/services/your-council-and-democracy/elections#europeanparliamentaryelections"&gt;tells me that I'm in the South West Region&lt;/a&gt;, which returns six members. Voting is by Regional List, where the parties are given members …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the EU elections on Thursday, I realize I've got to get my head round it all and decide who I'm voting for. The BANES website &lt;a href="http://www.bathnes.gov.uk/services/your-council-and-democracy/elections#europeanparliamentaryelections"&gt;tells me that I'm in the South West Region&lt;/a&gt;, which returns six members. Voting is by Regional List, where the parties are given members in proportion to their votes.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see Europe without the EU as an 'anarchy of nations'. With the EU it becomes closer to democracy. The benefits of such a democracy are:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less chance of war within Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The free movement of people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I'm in favour of the UK being part of the EU I can rule out UKIP, UK Independence Now, English Democrats and the BNP.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that leaves the manifestos of the Green Party, LibDems, Conservatives and Labour to read.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Green Party&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://greenparty.org.uk/assets/files/European%20Manifesto%202014.pdf"&gt;The Greens&lt;/a&gt; first. I took fright at this sentence:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we invest, we can provide good, stable jobs for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds harmless, but I take it to mean 'turn on the Keynesian taps', ie. public spending that will involve borrowing more, or taxing more, and taking people out of the wealth-creating private sector. Bad news for the economy. Just look at France.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phase out the European Value Added Tax. Currently, the EU requires member states to collect VAT, in part as a contribution to the budget of the EU. This is a regressive tax, because poorer people spend a higher portion of their income (rather than saving it). Green MEPs will argue for mandatory VAT to be scrapped, for governments to be allowed to determine how they raise this share of their contribution to EU budgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I do agree with.  I really hope the other parties have noticed this and get on board. Here's another good bit on democratic trade deals:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that only national parliaments and the European parliament can initiate trade deals. The situation whereby only the unelected Commission can initiate and take part in these processes but for a veto is undemocratic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make all trade deals transparently rather than behind closed doors. They impact on the lives of Europeans as much as any policy, and should be negotiated accountably in the open, not in secret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oops, they're in favour of the Financial Transaction Tax. Misguided in my view, financial transactions shouldn't be punished.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the Greens want to nationalise everything, but I think they've got a blind spot here. Private companies are creating a lot of wealth for us and working well, and the challenge is to regulate them properly, not to nationalise them. Having a monolithic bureaucracy run everything would be exasperating. Let the entrepreneurs contribute their ideas!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Green Quantitative Easing is bogus too. You only need to print money when inflation is too low, which may never happen. So you can't fund policies with it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like their animal welfare section, although I don't see why cloning and genetic modification are necessarily harmful to animals' welfare.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disagree with preventing private companies from running NHS hospitals and other services.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadly agree with their education and science policies.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greens are in favour of the free movement of people. Hurrah! They say:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in treating arrivals here in the way in which we would expect to be treated if we moved abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well said. Also, this greatly pleased me:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encourage the use of Free/Libre/Open Source software by all EU institutions and member state governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disappointed that Greens are against an EU army. I think this would be a step forward and a pre-requisite for disbanding national armies.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;LibDems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, now on to the &lt;a href="http://www.libdems.org.uk/european_election_manifesto_2014"&gt;LibDems&lt;/a&gt;.In the introduction to the manifesto, Nick Clegg says the LibDems are the only party that want to stay in the EU, but the Greens do too. Not a good start.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading on, there's a lot of good bits about freeing up trade within Europe, and setting up free trade agreements. Though they don't do as well as the greens in making these negotiations transparent and controlled by the parliament. Good that the LibDems are in favour of reducing export subsidies.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good, support for Europol and the EU arrest warrant.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure about the subsidies for renewables, but the EU super-grid is a good idea. Putting money into carbon capture and storage seems a disastrous policy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture and fisheries policies seem reasonable, although I'd like to see the subsidies abolished altogether.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good, they're in favour of EU expansion.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I'd not be unhappy at voting LibDem.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conservatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh dear, they want to hold an in-out referendum. I don't like referendums, it gives elected representatives an excuse for their poor performance. Also, questions are never that simple, and it's impossible to give a nuanced answer.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I disagree with this policy:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National parliaments able to work together to block unwanted European legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole point is that the EU parliament has democratic legitimacy and decides things at an EU level. National parliaments should confine themselves to national issues. Also, they're against an EU army. I'm in favour of an EU army!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This manifesto seems to repeat itself rather a lot.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a good bit:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have prevented a European ban on stem cell research, which would have undermined our ability to find cures to the most terrible diseases and damaged Britain’s life sciences industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to be a part of the Schengen area!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kept out of the Schengen open borders area,which allows citizens in mainland European Union nations to travel across borders without having their passports checked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Conservatives talk about cutting red tape, but want to check my papers at every turn! They've also misspent huge amounts of taxpayer's money on subsidising nuclear power:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;secured the first new nuclear power station for a generation at Hinkley Point&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not strong enough on the free movement of people.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Labour&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;a href="http://www.yourbritain.org.uk/uploads/editor/files/LABOUR_PARTY_euro_manifesto.pdf"&gt;Labour&lt;/a&gt;. Their 'web presence' is really confusing. Well, I find their analysis of the economic situation very unconvincing. Labour racked up a huge debt which we haven't even begun to pay off, and that's held back our recovery. They also let the public sector balloon, squeezing out the wealth-creating private sector. I don't want them applying their economic misconceptions at the EU too.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labour MEPs delivered measures to clamp down on bankers’ bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold on, it was Labour that contributed to the financial crisis by bailing out bankers in the first place! We can't undo that, but we can make banking more competitive. How many new banks have been started in the last decade? With competition, profits tend to zero.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labour MEPs moved to protect savers against losing everything by backing a new deposit guarantee to provide compensation for depositors if their bank goes bust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold on, someone who invests money in a bank shouldn't be bailed out by the tax payer if their investment fails.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll probably vote LibDem tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Proust On Memes II</title><link href="/proust-on-memes-ii.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-19T20:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-05-19T20:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-05-19:/proust-on-memes-ii.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following on from &lt;a href="/proust-on-memes.html"&gt;Proust On Memes&lt;/a&gt;:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A powerful idea communicates some of its power to the man who contradicts it. Partaking of the universal community of minds, it infiltrates, grafts itself on to, the mind of him whom it refutes,among other contiguous ideas, with the aid of which, counter …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following on from &lt;a href="/proust-on-memes.html"&gt;Proust On Memes&lt;/a&gt;:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A powerful idea communicates some of its power to the man who contradicts it. Partaking of the universal community of minds, it infiltrates, grafts itself on to, the mind of him whom it refutes,among other contiguous ideas, with the aid of which, counter attacking, he complements and corrects it; so that the final verdict is always to some extent the work of both parties to a discussion. It is to ideas which are not, strictly speaking, ideas at all,to ideas which, based on nothing, can find no foothold, no fraternal echo in the mind of the adversary, that the latter,grappling as it were with thin air, can find no word to say in answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Goodbye to my old profile photo</title><link href="/goodbye-to-my-old-profile-photo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-19T20:17:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-05-19T20:17:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-05-19:/goodbye-to-my-old-profile-photo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Profile Photo" src="/images/2014/ad91c65a33ee79edf84dc26defa1313c.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Profile Photo" src="/images/2014/ad91c65a33ee79edf84dc26defa1313c.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Proust On Memes</title><link href="/proust-on-memes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-04T12:54:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-05-04T12:54:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-05-04:/proust-on-memes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading In A Budding Grove. Proust writes about what strikes me as competing memes:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the communal life that is led by our ideas in the enclosure of our minds, there is a single one of those that makes us most happy which has not first sought, like a real …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading In A Budding Grove. Proust writes about what strikes me as competing memes:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the communal life that is led by our ideas in the enclosure of our minds, there is a single one of those that makes us most happy which has not first sought, like a real parasite, and won from an alien but neighbouring idea the greater part of the strength that it originally lacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Password length, range and strength</title><link href="/password-length-range-and-strength.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-19T14:26:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-04-19T14:26:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2014-04-19:/password-length-range-and-strength.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I advised my friend to use uppercase / lowercase / numbers / special-characters in her password to make it more secure. On hearing this my friends Bill and Andy errupted into a disputatious frenzy, arguing that password length is more important than the range of characters. I was shaken enough to try and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I advised my friend to use uppercase / lowercase / numbers / special-characters in her password to make it more secure. On hearing this my friends Bill and Andy errupted into a disputatious frenzy, arguing that password length is more important than the range of characters. I was shaken enough to try and find out if they were right. I opened up LibreOffice Calc and made the following graph:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Password Strength" src="/images/2014/password_strength.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blue is for passwords just using the 26 lower case letters, and the red is for 67 alphanumerics. The idea is that the horizontal axis is the strength of the password, and the height of the column is the number of characters you need to achieve that strength. For example, say you want a password strength of 1 x 10^12^ variations, you can see that it requires a password length of about 8.5 charaters of lowercase, and 6.5 characters of alphanumeric.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, assuming this graph and all the assumptions are correct, who is right? I concede that they are! But is that the whole story? What if you're using words? Then the whole thing changes. We need another graph. Bill, Andy?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Update 2014-04-19 14:41]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XKCD has a &lt;a href="http://xkcd.com/936/"&gt;good take&lt;/a&gt; on this,  so four easy-to-remember random words.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Various Photos</title><link href="/various-photos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-08T21:48:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-10-08T21:48:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-10-08:/various-photos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pollution" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130611_093234.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a photo when they came to test for air pollution at my house. Thankfully no pollution was found.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tube" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130617_205502.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Daily Mirror" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130617_205903.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A paper from the day I was born.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Horse" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130726_180255.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was walking to pick up a package from a depot outside Bristol, and I came upon a horse.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130819_191701.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A delicious meal …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pollution" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130611_093234.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a photo when they came to test for air pollution at my house. Thankfully no pollution was found.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tube" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130617_205502.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Daily Mirror" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130617_205903.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A paper from the day I was born.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Horse" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130726_180255.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was walking to pick up a package from a depot outside Bristol, and I came upon a horse.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130819_191701.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A delicious meal at Andy's house.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Oxford" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130909_130827.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo from visiting Matt in Oxford.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ben's Cookies" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130921_164107.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Ben's Cookies t-shirt had to be thrown out. It was just too old and raggedy.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Skip photos!</title><link href="/skip-photos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-08T21:38:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-10-08T21:38:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-10-08:/skip-photos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130620_154321.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130716_174223.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 3" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130806_080724.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130620_154321.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130716_174223.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 3" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130806_080724.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="skip-watch"></category></entry><entry><title>Strange Fits of Passion</title><link href="/strange-fits-of-passion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-04T22:31:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-09-04T22:31:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-09-04:/strange-fits-of-passion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Strange_Fits_of_Passion_Have_I_Known"&gt;Strange fits of passion&lt;/a&gt; have I known:&lt;br&gt;
And I will dare to tell,&lt;br&gt;
But in the Lover's ear alone,&lt;br&gt;
What once to me befell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is where the title of the Anita Shreve book comes from. It's one of those books where you know what's going to happen …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Strange_Fits_of_Passion_Have_I_Known"&gt;Strange fits of passion&lt;/a&gt; have I known:&lt;br&gt;
And I will dare to tell,&lt;br&gt;
But in the Lover's ear alone,&lt;br&gt;
What once to me befell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is where the title of the Anita Shreve book comes from. It's one of those books where you know what's going to happen from the beginning. It's not uplifting, but human qualities, good and bad, are well described. The subject and story are very much of their time. In chronicling the fictional story of the protagonist, Shreve chronicles the real attitudes of society in that period.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Scientific Alliance: Phase Out Subsidies</title><link href="/scientific-alliance-phase-out-subsidies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-24T20:34:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-08-24T20:34:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-08-24:/scientific-alliance-phase-out-subsidies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href="http://www.scientific-alliance.org/scientific-alliance-newsletter/phasing-out-subsidies"&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; and was moved to write the following email:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Scientific Alliance,  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read with interest your news letter entitled Phasing Out Subsidies:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.scientific-alliance.org/scientific-alliance-newsletter/phasing-out-subsidies  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that subsidies for renewables should be phased out, surely subsidies for all sources of energy …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href="http://www.scientific-alliance.org/scientific-alliance-newsletter/phasing-out-subsidies"&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; and was moved to write the following email:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Scientific Alliance,  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read with interest your news letter entitled Phasing Out Subsidies:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.scientific-alliance.org/scientific-alliance-newsletter/phasing-out-subsidies  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that subsidies for renewables should be phased out, surely subsidies for all sources of energy are equally bad. For example, why is there no mention of the £2.3bn annual subsidy that nuclear power receives?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards,  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tony Locke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Priority Of Pensions If Company Goes Into Liquidation</title><link href="/priority-of-pensions-if-company-goes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-12T22:13:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-08-12T22:13:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-08-12:/priority-of-pensions-if-company-goes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Opinion &lt;a href="http://moneyweek.com/right-side-did-the-supreme-court-just-write-down-your-pension/"&gt;seems&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/newsbysector/banksandfinance/10200923/No-priority-for-pensions-when-companies-go-bust.html"&gt;divided&lt;/a&gt; on whether it's a good thing that the UK Supreme Court has ruled that pensioners don't get priority if a company goes into liquidation. I like the idea of the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/personal-pensions-your-rights/stakeholder-pensions"&gt;stakeholder pension&lt;/a&gt;, which sidesteps this problem.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Opinion &lt;a href="http://moneyweek.com/right-side-did-the-supreme-court-just-write-down-your-pension/"&gt;seems&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/newsbysector/banksandfinance/10200923/No-priority-for-pensions-when-companies-go-bust.html"&gt;divided&lt;/a&gt; on whether it's a good thing that the UK Supreme Court has ruled that pensioners don't get priority if a company goes into liquidation. I like the idea of the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/personal-pensions-your-rights/stakeholder-pensions"&gt;stakeholder pension&lt;/a&gt;, which sidesteps this problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>New fridge</title><link href="/new-fridge.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-08T17:32:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-06-08T17:32:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-06-08:/new-fridge.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The door of the freezer compartment of my fridge has broken, and as it's quite old I've &lt;a href="http://www.currys.co.uk/gbuk/household-appliances/refrigeration/fridge-freezers/beko-cxf5083w-fridge-freezer-white-12635520-pdt.html"&gt;bought a new one&lt;/a&gt;. Have I made a good choice? Btw, I've been getting lots of comment spam recently so I've disabled anonymous comments :-o&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The door of the freezer compartment of my fridge has broken, and as it's quite old I've &lt;a href="http://www.currys.co.uk/gbuk/household-appliances/refrigeration/fridge-freezers/beko-cxf5083w-fridge-freezer-white-12635520-pdt.html"&gt;bought a new one&lt;/a&gt;. Have I made a good choice? Btw, I've been getting lots of comment spam recently so I've disabled anonymous comments :-o&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Polifesto now has comments</title><link href="/polifesto-now-has-comments.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-28T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-05-28T20:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-05-28:/polifesto-now-has-comments.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You can now comment on a policy in Polifesto. Here's a &lt;a href="http://www.polifesto.com/view_policy?policy_key=ag9zfnBvbGlmZXN0by1ocmRyDwsSBlBvbGljeRjaoKsCDA"&gt;policy with a couple of comments&lt;/a&gt;. This policy, 'Citizen's Income' is also the highest rated policy, with 300 points. One of the next things to do is a notification system where you can received email notifications for new versions …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You can now comment on a policy in Polifesto. Here's a &lt;a href="http://www.polifesto.com/view_policy?policy_key=ag9zfnBvbGlmZXN0by1ocmRyDwsSBlBvbGljeRjaoKsCDA"&gt;policy with a couple of comments&lt;/a&gt;. This policy, 'Citizen's Income' is also the highest rated policy, with 300 points. One of the next things to do is a notification system where you can received email notifications for new versions and comments for a particular policy. As ever, let me know what you think...&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Polifesto Using Creole</title><link href="/polifesto-using-creole.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-11T13:48:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-05-11T13:48:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-05-11:/polifesto-using-creole.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.polifesto.com/"&gt;Polifesto&lt;/a&gt; used to use a subset of HTML5 to mark up policies. I thought that this might be a bit unforgiving for users because there'd be an error if the markup wasn't valid XML. Influenced by a &lt;a href="http://www.wilfred.me.uk/blog/2012/07/30/why-markdown-is-not-my-favourite-language/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I'd give &lt;a href="http://wikicreole.org/wiki/Creole1.0"&gt;Creole&lt;/a&gt; a try. Let me know what …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.polifesto.com/"&gt;Polifesto&lt;/a&gt; used to use a subset of HTML5 to mark up policies. I thought that this might be a bit unforgiving for users because there'd be an error if the markup wasn't valid XML. Influenced by a &lt;a href="http://www.wilfred.me.uk/blog/2012/07/30/why-markdown-is-not-my-favourite-language/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I'd give &lt;a href="http://wikicreole.org/wiki/Creole1.0"&gt;Creole&lt;/a&gt; a try. Let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="polifesto"></category></entry><entry><title>BrowserId Better Than OpenId</title><link href="/browserid-better-than-openid.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-08T21:47:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-05-08T21:47:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-05-08:/browserid-better-than-openid.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been a long-time fan of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenID"&gt;OpenId&lt;/a&gt;, but I now think &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BrowserID"&gt;BrowserId&lt;/a&gt; is better. Here are the two main reasons why:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With BrowserId the user enters an email address, whereas with OpenId the user enters a URL. Most users already have an email address that they remember, and can type …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been a long-time fan of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenID"&gt;OpenId&lt;/a&gt;, but I now think &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BrowserID"&gt;BrowserId&lt;/a&gt; is better. Here are the two main reasons why:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With BrowserId the user enters an email address, whereas with OpenId the user enters a URL. Most users already have an email address that they remember, and can type easily. With OpenId and its URLs, it's more complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With OpenId, you had to work out whether you had an OpenId or not. If not then you had to go and obtain one at a separate web site. With Mozilla Persona (an implementation of BrowserId) any email address you have will work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've put my money where my mouth is and replaced OpenId with Persona on &lt;a href="http://www.polifesto.com/"&gt;Polifesto&lt;/a&gt;. Let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Git versus Mercurial</title><link href="/git-versus-mercurial.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-04T18:17:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-05-04T18:17:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-05-04:/git-versus-mercurial.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know very little about the religious war of Git versus Mercurial, but ignorance has never stopped me from having a firm opinion.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come down on the side of Git for these reasons:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Local Version Numbers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mercurial has the idea of local version numbers as well as universal hashes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know very little about the religious war of Git versus Mercurial, but ignorance has never stopped me from having a firm opinion.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come down on the side of Git for these reasons:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Local Version Numbers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mercurial has the idea of local version numbers as well as universal hashes. I don't like these extra local version numbers because it's an additional feature that muddies the waters without really contributing anything. Git uses hashes that are universal. You can specify versions locally in an easy way using the tilde notation.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Approach To History&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, local version numbers is just an annoyance. The big difference for me is that for Mercurial, history is literal, but for Git, history is a story. If you ask someone what they did yesterday evening, they'll say something like, "I watched Holby City", they don't say "I sat on the bean bag next to the sofa at 20:00 and put the TV on and changed the channel to BBC1 and then watched the screen for approximately 1 hour...". The first is the Git answer, where you summarize the salient points after they occur. The second is the Mercurial approach where you give a verbatim replay of the events as they occurred. So with Git you're encouraged to tidy up your history before you push to a public repository. With Mercurial you're encouraged to view history as immutable, and however you got to the point you're at, that's what you make public.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Indiscriminate Push&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Git you get to explicitly push individual branches to a remote repository. With Mercurial, the push command pushes all branches to the remote repository, which isn't necessarily what you want. Mercurial tries to get round this with bookmarks, but I feel that this is a hack, and that Git's branches are more elegant. With Mercurial, branches are part of the commit, but with Git, branches are references held outside the commit. The Git approach turns out to be the way to go.  &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Film makers, could you use the Monopoly model of time travel in all future films please?</title><link href="/film-makers-could-you-use-monopoly.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-28T14:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-04-28T14:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-04-28:/film-makers-could-you-use-monopoly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Watching &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Looper_%28film%29"&gt;Looper&lt;/a&gt; last night I became exasperated with film makers for not getting time travel right. The model of time travel that they use suffers from the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grandfather_paradox"&gt;grandfather paradox&lt;/a&gt;. After the film I tried to explain time (with diagrams!!) to my friends, but everyone left immediately. I'm going to try …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Watching &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Looper_%28film%29"&gt;Looper&lt;/a&gt; last night I became exasperated with film makers for not getting time travel right. The model of time travel that they use suffers from the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grandfather_paradox"&gt;grandfather paradox&lt;/a&gt;. After the film I tried to explain time (with diagrams!!) to my friends, but everyone left immediately. I'm going to try again via the medium of the internet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my childhood I spent lots of happy hours playing Monopoly with my brother. He usually won. Anyway, when you look at a game of Monopoly you can vaguely tell how far through the game you are. If there aren't any properties bought, and everyone's still in the game, you know you're at the beginning. If there are just two players left and there are hotels everywhere you know you're probably nearing the end.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monopoly is like the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiverse"&gt;multiverse&lt;/a&gt;. The state of the game is like a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universe#Multiverse_theory"&gt;universe&lt;/a&gt;. In the real world if you take a sequence of photos, say of an ice cube melting, if the order of the photos get muddled up you can easily put them back in order.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, with Monopoly if you took a sequences of photos of the game and then muddled them up, someone could probably put them back in order.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is that in Monopoly you can sometimes go back in time. A common example is getting the 'Go Back To The Old Kent Road!' card. In this case the person putting the muddled photos back in order might get it slightly wrong.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or everyone could actually decide to go back in time by selling houses, hotels and properties. If they did that, they could make it really difficult for someone to reconstruct the order of the photos. This is time travel, and you can see that there it doesn't suffer from the grandfather paradox, or any other problems.&lt;br&gt;
So film makers, could you use the Monopoly model of time travel in all future films please?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>New Model Army</title><link href="/new-model-army.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-26T20:23:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-04-26T20:23:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-04-26:/new-model-army.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Listening to the In Our Time &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b01rw1k7"&gt;programme on the Putney Debates&lt;/a&gt; brought home to me how much &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adam_Roberts_%28British_writer%29"&gt;Adam Roberts&lt;/a&gt; had drawn on the historical New Model Army in his book of the same name.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday last week I went camping in Cornwall:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BH5l96jCAAEZKxA.jpg:large"&gt;&lt;img alt="New Model Army" height="320" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BH5l96jCAAEZKxA.jpg:large" width="320"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;taking the book with me. Not having …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Listening to the In Our Time &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b01rw1k7"&gt;programme on the Putney Debates&lt;/a&gt; brought home to me how much &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adam_Roberts_%28British_writer%29"&gt;Adam Roberts&lt;/a&gt; had drawn on the historical New Model Army in his book of the same name.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday last week I went camping in Cornwall:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BH5l96jCAAEZKxA.jpg:large"&gt;&lt;img alt="New Model Army" height="320" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BH5l96jCAAEZKxA.jpg:large" width="320"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;taking the book with me. Not having read Adam Roberts before I had no idea what to expect. I started reading, and was very impressed with what I found. There's a mixture of excellent ideas mixed with erudition, and action scenes that I can only describe as punchy. Roberts is a real student of the craft of writing. I'm looking forward to reading more from him.  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Desktop sharing for Ubuntu 13.04</title><link href="/desktop-sharing-for-ubuntu-1304.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-19T13:38:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-04-19T13:38:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-04-19:/desktop-sharing-for-ubuntu-1304.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are some instructions for setting up your Ubuntu 13.04 machine so that you can share your desktop with someone else over the internet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, first of all go to the Dash (the thing in the top left of the screen) and type &lt;code&gt;desktop sharing&lt;/code&gt;. Click on the &lt;code&gt;Desktop …&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are some instructions for setting up your Ubuntu 13.04 machine so that you can share your desktop with someone else over the internet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, first of all go to the Dash (the thing in the top left of the screen) and type &lt;code&gt;desktop sharing&lt;/code&gt;. Click on the &lt;code&gt;Desktop Sharing&lt;/code&gt; app to start it. In its preferences make the settings look like:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sharing" src="/images/2013/sharing.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;code&gt;Close&lt;/code&gt;, and your computer should now be ready for someone else to connect. The thing is that they need to know the address to connect to. To find this out, do a Google search for &lt;code&gt;what is my ip address&lt;/code&gt; and it'll come up with your public IP address. Something like:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot" src="/images/2013/Screenshot_from_2013-04-19_13_33_20.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell the IP address to the person you want to share your desktop with. Ubuntu will prompt you to allow / refuse when someone tries to connect. Note that your IP address may change every now and then. You can use a host name that doesn't change using something like &lt;a href="https://www.noip.com/"&gt;NoIP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Defamation Bill: A confusing vote from the Lib Dems</title><link href="/defamation-bill-disappointing-vote-from.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-18T12:47:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-04-18T12:47:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-04-18:/defamation-bill-disappointing-vote-from.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've &lt;a href="/abolish-libel-laws.html"&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="/pass-libel-reform-bil.html"&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt; about the Defamation Bill, and I've written again to my MP Don Foster:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading the &lt;a href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201213/cmhansrd/cm130416/debtext/130416-0003.htm#13041655000001"&gt;Commons debate on 16th April on the Defamation Bill&lt;/a&gt;, I was disappointed to see that you voted for rejecting the Lords' second amendment which would have restricted companies from suing individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've &lt;a href="/abolish-libel-laws.html"&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="/pass-libel-reform-bil.html"&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt; about the Defamation Bill, and I've written again to my MP Don Foster:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading the &lt;a href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201213/cmhansrd/cm130416/debtext/130416-0003.htm#13041655000001"&gt;Commons debate on 16th April on the Defamation Bill&lt;/a&gt;, I was disappointed to see that you voted for rejecting the Lords' second amendment which would have restricted companies from suing individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Don's office have replied with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lib Julian Huppert and Simon Hughes managed to get the Government to agree to a revised amendment. You can read about it &lt;a href="http://www.libdemvoice.org/julian-huppert-writes-update-on-the-defamation-bill-34138.html#utm_source=libdemvoice.org&amp;amp;utm_medium=redirect&amp;amp;utm_campaign=url"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a bit confused as to why the Lib Dems voted in favour of rejecting the Lords' second amendment, but then seem to be including it again. I think I probably don't understand these things properly!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Prime Minister</title><link href="/the-prime-minister.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-30T15:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-30T15:45:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-03-30:/the-prime-minister.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading He Knew He Was Right led me on to The Prime Minister. This is a sensitively written and very enjoyable story, part of a soap opera really, or to be fancy a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Novel_sequence#Roman-fleuve"&gt;roman fleuve&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes Trollope talks directly to the reader. I don't like this as it breaks the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading He Knew He Was Right led me on to The Prime Minister. This is a sensitively written and very enjoyable story, part of a soap opera really, or to be fancy a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Novel_sequence#Roman-fleuve"&gt;roman fleuve&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes Trollope talks directly to the reader. I don't like this as it breaks the illusion of being transported to a different world, and it reminds one that it's a book. People might say that this is post-modern, but whatever it is I don't like it. Jane Austen did all that 'dear reader' stuff and I think that perhaps that's where Trollope got it from. Thankfully it's out of fashion nowadays and I'd like it to stay that way.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we're on this kind of topic, I don't like it in films or books where at the beginning someone looks into the middle distance and says, 'it all started on a damp Tuesday in Mayfair...' and then they go on to tell the story. I think Heart Of Darkness starts like this. It happens a lot in films too. I don't like it because it's like the story has already happened and it's all predetermined.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Hellstrom's Hive</title><link href="/hellstroms-hive.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-26T19:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-26T19:59:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-03-26:/hellstroms-hive.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read Frank Herbert's Dune while living temporarily in Wells. A unique time. So Hellstrom's Hive is my second FH, lent to me by Zoe through Charlotte. It's a book of extremely high quality. Written in the the late nineteen sixties, it doesn't feel dated and has all you hope …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read Frank Herbert's Dune while living temporarily in Wells. A unique time. So Hellstrom's Hive is my second FH, lent to me by Zoe through Charlotte. It's a book of extremely high quality. Written in the the late nineteen sixties, it doesn't feel dated and has all you hope for, including very sharp writing, excitement, and good ideas.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I didn't know it was written by Herbert, I wouldn't have guessed it was the same author that wrote Dune. Frank Herbert really has risen in my regard of him.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Photos Of Breakfasts And Other Meals</title><link href="/photos-of-breakfasts-and-other-meals.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-25T22:23:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-25T22:23:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-03-25:/photos-of-breakfasts-and-other-meals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_120239.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Red" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_124738.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_120254.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 3" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_120245.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 4" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_124807.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 5" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_124814.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_164106.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Scarf" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_135851.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_182304.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 3" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_185356.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 4" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_182311.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 5" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_185404.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 6" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_185413.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 7" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_185424.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 8" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130202_115235.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 9" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_110628.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 10" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_113101.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 11" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_114132.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 12" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_114144.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 13" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_114151.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 14" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_114231.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 15" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130210_155450.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 16" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130210_171658.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pipe 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130211_103236.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pipe 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130211_103328.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Under Stairs" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130211_103352.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cupboard" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130211_103428.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kindle" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130212_215255.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 17" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_113255.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 18" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_115638.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Standing 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_132029.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Standing 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_132038.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Jeans" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_175407.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 19" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130202_115242.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 20" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130316_121425.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 21" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130323_115124.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Shirt" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130325_212939.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_120239.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Red" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_124738.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_120254.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 3" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_120245.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 4" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_124807.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Breakfast 5" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130119_124814.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_164106.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Scarf" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_135851.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_182304.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 3" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_185356.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 4" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_182311.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 5" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_185404.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 6" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_185413.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 7" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130127_185424.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 8" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130202_115235.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 9" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_110628.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 10" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_113101.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 11" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_114132.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 12" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_114144.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 13" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_114151.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 14" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_114231.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 15" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130210_155450.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 16" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130210_171658.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pipe 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130211_103236.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pipe 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130211_103328.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Under Stairs" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130211_103352.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cupboard" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130211_103428.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kindle" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130212_215255.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 17" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_113255.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 18" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_115638.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Standing 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_132029.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Standing 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_132038.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Jeans" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130216_175407.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 19" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130202_115242.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 20" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130316_121425.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Meal 21" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130323_115124.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Shirt" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130325_212939.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Snowy Journey To Work</title><link href="/snowy-journey-to-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-25T22:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-25T22:02:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-03-25:/snowy-journey-to-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130118_082046.jpg"&gt;
  Snowy On 18th Jan 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130118_123920.jpg"&gt;
  View From Alexandra Park On The Way Home From Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130118_082046.jpg"&gt;
  Snowy On 18th Jan 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snow 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130118_123920.jpg"&gt;
  View From Alexandra Park On The Way Home From Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Skip February 2013</title><link href="/skip-2013-02-07.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-25T21:58:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-25T21:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-03-25:/skip-2013-02-07.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_144726.jpg"&gt;
  9th February 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130207_174013.jpg"&gt;
  7th February 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 1" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130209_144726.jpg"&gt;
  9th February 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip 2" src="/images/2013/IMG_20130207_174013.jpg"&gt;
  7th February 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</content><category term="skip-watch"></category></entry><entry><title>Ban On Pesticides Harmful To Bees</title><link href="/ban-on-pesticides-harmful-to-bees.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-14T21:25:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-14T21:25:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-03-14:/ban-on-pesticides-harmful-to-bees.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just been asked to &lt;a href="https://secure.38degrees.org.uk/page/share/bees-urgent-vote"&gt;send a letter to my MP&lt;/a&gt; about the proposal to ban some pesticides that &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/mar/13/owen-paterson-ban-pesticides-bees"&gt;may be harmful to bees&lt;/a&gt;. I don't know enough about this to write to my MP, but from what I've read scientists haven't reached a settled view on it, and so …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just been asked to &lt;a href="https://secure.38degrees.org.uk/page/share/bees-urgent-vote"&gt;send a letter to my MP&lt;/a&gt; about the proposal to ban some pesticides that &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/mar/13/owen-paterson-ban-pesticides-bees"&gt;may be harmful to bees&lt;/a&gt;. I don't know enough about this to write to my MP, but from what I've read scientists haven't reached a settled view on it, and so more research is needed, and so I support the ban.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Pass The Libel Reform Bil</title><link href="/pass-libel-reform-bil.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-09T18:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-09T18:57:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-03-09:/pass-libel-reform-bil.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just emailed &lt;a href="http://skeptical-voter.org/wiki/index.php?title=Don_Foster"&gt;my MP&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href="http://www.libelreform.org/dontkillthebill?"&gt;Libel Reform Bill&lt;/a&gt;:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Don, I'm aware that you're a supporter of libel reform in the UK and I'm writing to you as a constituent to ask you to take the necessary steps to ensure the bill is passed before the end of …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just emailed &lt;a href="http://skeptical-voter.org/wiki/index.php?title=Don_Foster"&gt;my MP&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href="http://www.libelreform.org/dontkillthebill?"&gt;Libel Reform Bill&lt;/a&gt;:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Don, I'm aware that you're a supporter of libel reform in the UK and I'm writing to you as a constituent to ask you to take the necessary steps to ensure the bill is passed before the end of the parliamentary session. I'm concerned that the bill has been 'hijacked' by those seeking to impose press regulation, and I feel that it's important that the original intent of the bill remains intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Effect Of MOOCs On Research</title><link href="/the-effect-of-moocs-on-research.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-10T20:35:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-02-10T20:35:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-02-10:/the-effect-of-moocs-on-research.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jonathan sent me a link to a blog post called &lt;a href="http://themagnetisalwayson.com/moocs-as-capital-biased-technological-change/"&gt;MOOCs as capital-biased technological change&lt;/a&gt;. It argues that the effect of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course"&gt;MOOC&lt;/a&gt;s will be to reduce demand for university teaching, which is what supports creative research, and so society's academic output will decline.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd argue that if MOOCs lower …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jonathan sent me a link to a blog post called &lt;a href="http://themagnetisalwayson.com/moocs-as-capital-biased-technological-change/"&gt;MOOCs as capital-biased technological change&lt;/a&gt;. It argues that the effect of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course"&gt;MOOC&lt;/a&gt;s will be to reduce demand for university teaching, which is what supports creative research, and so society's academic output will decline.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd argue that if MOOCs lower the cost of teaching, the money saved can (and should) be spent on research, and so the number of people paid to increase the sum of knowledge would go up.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Nuclear subsidies</title><link href="/nuclear-subsidies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-31T19:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-01-31T19:24:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-01-31:/nuclear-subsidies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've seen a couple of good articles on UK nuclear subsidies recently. The &lt;a href="http://www.energyfair.org.uk/home/nuclear-subsidy"&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt; is by Gerry Wolff. Here's an excerpt:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no justification of any kind for subsidising nuclear power and there is every reason to ensure that nuclear power is not on the list of technologies …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've seen a couple of good articles on UK nuclear subsidies recently. The &lt;a href="http://www.energyfair.org.uk/home/nuclear-subsidy"&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt; is by Gerry Wolff. Here's an excerpt:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no justification of any kind for subsidising nuclear power and there is every reason to ensure that nuclear power is not on the list of technologies that would be eligible for support via the CfD. We may thus avoid what would otherwise be the considerable risk of creating nuclear white elephants that would be paid for mainly by consumers that are least able to afford them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/taxpayer-billions-could-be-secretly-funnelled-to-edf-to-underwrite-cost-of-proposed-power-station-at-hinkley-point-8473810.html"&gt;second article&lt;/a&gt; is by Tom Bawden in The Independent. He says:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billions of pounds of taxpayers money could be secretly funnelled to the French state nuclear company Edf to underwrite the cost of its proposed new power station at Hinkley Point in Somerset, it emerged today.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The energy bill has quietly granted energy secretary Ed Davey the power to keep contract details of the crucial Hinkley Point C project a secret if he decides it is commercially sensitive to disclose them, an analysis of the bill has revealed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts condemned the provision, saying it paves the way for the government to write a cheque for billions of dollars to cover the cost of budget over-runs or building delays at Hinkley Point, without the public or parliament ever finding out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Things to fix in house, in BitBucket!</title><link href="/things-to-fix-in-house-in-bitbucket.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-29T21:29:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-01-29T21:29:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-01-29:/things-to-fix-in-house-in-bitbucket.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by an &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredenterprise/2013/01/this-old-house/"&gt;article in Wired&lt;/a&gt;, I've put all the bugs in my house &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/tlocke/house/"&gt;on BitBucket&lt;/a&gt;. To see them, click on the &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/tlocke/house/issues?status=new&amp;amp;status=open"&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; link. To report a new bug you have to sign up to BitBucket, then create a new issue.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by an &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredenterprise/2013/01/this-old-house/"&gt;article in Wired&lt;/a&gt;, I've put all the bugs in my house &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/tlocke/house/"&gt;on BitBucket&lt;/a&gt;. To see them, click on the &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/tlocke/house/issues?status=new&amp;amp;status=open"&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; link. To report a new bug you have to sign up to BitBucket, then create a new issue.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Jobs on PowerPoint</title><link href="/jobs-on-powerpoint.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-04T20:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-01-04T20:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2013-01-04:/jobs-on-powerpoint.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I forgot to mention this in my last
&lt;a href="/steve-jobs-biography.html"&gt;post on the Steve Jobs biography&lt;/a&gt;, but I was amused to read Jobs' views on PowerPoint:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first things Jobs did during the product review process was ban PowerPoints. "I hate the way people use slide presentations instead of thinking …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I forgot to mention this in my last
&lt;a href="/steve-jobs-biography.html"&gt;post on the Steve Jobs biography&lt;/a&gt;, but I was amused to read Jobs' views on PowerPoint:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first things Jobs did during the product review process was ban PowerPoints. "I hate the way people use slide presentations instead of thinking," Jobs later recalled. "People would confront a problem by creating a presentation. I wanted them to engage, to hash things out at the table, rather than show a bunch of slides. People who know what they're talking about don't need PowerPoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel the same!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Bikers</title><link href="/bikers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-12-29T17:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-12-29T17:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-12-29:/bikers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201023.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201124.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 3" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201129.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 4" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201137.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 5" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201241.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 6" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201249.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201023.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201124.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 3" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201129.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 4" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201137.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 5" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201241.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Biker 6" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121221_201249.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Skip on 2nd December 2012</title><link href="/skip-on-2nd-december-2012.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-12-29T17:32:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-12-29T17:32:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-12-29:/skip-on-2nd-december-2012.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121202_135800.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121202_135800.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="skip-watch"></category></entry><entry><title>Steve Jobs' biography</title><link href="/steve-jobs-biography.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-12-27T18:43:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-12-27T18:43:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-12-27:/steve-jobs-biography.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File%3ASteve_Jobs_and_Bill_Gates_(522695099).jpg" title="By Joi Ito from Inbamura, Japan (Steve Jobs and Bill Gates on Flickr) [CC-BY-2.0 (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0)], via Wikimedia Commons"&gt;&lt;img alt="Steve Jobs and Bill Gates (522695099)" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a2/Steve_Jobs_and_Bill_Gates_%28522695099%29.jpg/512px-Steve_Jobs_and_Bill_Gates_%28522695099%29.jpg" width="512"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had norovirus since Saturday night. That first night was the worst, and it got much better after the first 24 hours. Now I feel achy and tired. During my convalescence, I've been reading Walter Isaacson's biography of Steve Jobs, which I borrowed from Wayne at work, after I saw …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File%3ASteve_Jobs_and_Bill_Gates_(522695099).jpg" title="By Joi Ito from Inbamura, Japan (Steve Jobs and Bill Gates on Flickr) [CC-BY-2.0 (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0)], via Wikimedia Commons"&gt;&lt;img alt="Steve Jobs and Bill Gates (522695099)" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a2/Steve_Jobs_and_Bill_Gates_%28522695099%29.jpg/512px-Steve_Jobs_and_Bill_Gates_%28522695099%29.jpg" width="512"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had norovirus since Saturday night. That first night was the worst, and it got much better after the first 24 hours. Now I feel achy and tired. During my convalescence, I've been reading Walter Isaacson's biography of Steve Jobs, which I borrowed from Wayne at work, after I saw him reading it at lunch time. I've always sort of admired Jobs.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Wayne said, 'Jobs wasn't a fan of openness, so you won't agree with him on his end-to-end control of the system'. Indeed, there is a running tension in the book between open and closed systems. I wonder if there is indeed a contradiction? The book was a bit loose with its idea of open and closed, citing Microsoft as taking the opposite approach to Apple by licensing Windows to run on any PC hardware. To me, Windows is not open, it is firmly in the proprietary camp. Openness can't be nailed down entirely, but from a legal point of view I'd say that any code should be Open Source, open standards should be used, and any content should come with an open content license such as the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike licence. Ideally the hardware itself should be distributed under an &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TAPR_Open_Hardware_License"&gt;open hardware licence&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, under this definition of openness, is it possible to give the user the integrated user experience that Apple claim to give their users?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd argue that GNU / Linux distributions such as Debian, with it's package management system, give a much more seamless experience that either OSX or Windows when it comes to installing / un-installing software. With Debian you install all software in a standard way, from a standard repository and then the system keeps it up-to-date for you. Everything works together. With Windows and Mac you have to hunt around on the internet for the correct version of the installer for your OS version and then download the file and then run the installer. When an upgrade comes out, how do you know? It's never been clear to me why Windows and Mac users put up with this. Perhaps Macs and Windows have 'app stores' now. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Apple_Inc._slogans#Apple_II"&gt;Welcome Apple and Microsoft. Seriously.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I think I got a bit carried away there. Supposed to be reviewing a book.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jobs' difficult personality, together with his illness later in life, gives a sadness to the book, but his can-do attitude is inspiring, and his passion for design struck a chord with me.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Surface Detail</title><link href="/surface-detail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-11-22T15:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-11-22T15:02:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-11-22:/surface-detail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you know, I've been a fan of Iain Banks since Karen at Uni lent me The Wasp Factory in maybe 1992. Looking in the library I saw a big fat book with a Culture style cover and so I borrowed it forthwith. I do like the Culture Minds and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you know, I've been a fan of Iain Banks since Karen at Uni lent me The Wasp Factory in maybe 1992. Looking in the library I saw a big fat book with a Culture style cover and so I borrowed it forthwith. I do like the Culture Minds and their dialogue, although I don't like the funny formatting of their exchanges. In fact, that's a general thing. I don't like it when authors deviate from normal prose and format things in a wacky way. For example, I dislike it when authors format an exchange of emails, as emails. Or tweets, letters or texts. Even Trollope does this with letters. I don't like having to parse a letter, noticing the date it was sent and the address etc. Maybe it's laziness, but I think actually it's that I like to know when I've ingested the requisite information. If it's conventional prose, then I know that I've got all the info because the information is digital. It's analogue information that I can't handle! This has turned into a big paragraph of rant, sorry about that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Here be angry farmers...</title><link href="/here-be-angry-farmers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-17T22:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-10-17T22:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-10-17:/here-be-angry-farmers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Went for a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/doitproperly/status/257740779672449025"&gt;walk with Andy&lt;/a&gt; and family on Sunday.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Foliage" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121014_154929.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit further on we encountered an angry farmer :-o&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Went for a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/doitproperly/status/257740779672449025"&gt;walk with Andy&lt;/a&gt; and family on Sunday.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Foliage" src="/images/2012/IMG_20121014_154929.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit further on we encountered an angry farmer :-o&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Galactic North</title><link href="/galactic-north.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-17T21:21:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-10-17T21:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-10-17:/galactic-north.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I felt a need for some sci-fi and so I went to the library after work and miraculously it was open. There was a single Alasdair Reynolds that I hadn't read, Galactic North. I snapped it up and enjoyed a collection of novellas and short stories, all set in Revelation …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I felt a need for some sci-fi and so I went to the library after work and miraculously it was open. There was a single Alasdair Reynolds that I hadn't read, Galactic North. I snapped it up and enjoyed a collection of novellas and short stories, all set in Revelation Space. Immensely enjoyable. A few days later I borrowed Iain M Banks' Surface Detail which I'm reading at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Archiving</title><link href="/archiving_30.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-30T18:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-30T18:24:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-30:/archiving_30.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;More &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/2612"&gt;archiving pictures...&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's an old shirt that I'm throwing out because it's got holes in and people have started making comments about it. I always feel a bit emotional at clothes that were around when my Mum was alive.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Old Shirt" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120930_175746.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;More &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/2612"&gt;archiving pictures...&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's an old shirt that I'm throwing out because it's got holes in and people have started making comments about it. I always feel a bit emotional at clothes that were around when my Mum was alive.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Old Shirt" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120930_175746.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Archiving</title><link href="/archiving_25.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-25T21:25:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-25T21:25:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-25:/archiving_25.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most of this &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/2414"&gt;latest batch&lt;/a&gt; are from my first year at Uni. Looking over them coincided with the start of the academic year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most of this &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/2414"&gt;latest batch&lt;/a&gt; are from my first year at Uni. Looking over them coincided with the start of the academic year.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Archiving</title><link href="/archiving_22.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-22T17:56:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-22T17:56:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-22:/archiving_22.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's the &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/2046"&gt;next batch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's the &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/2046"&gt;next batch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Shine</title><link href="/shine.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-22T14:53:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-22T14:53:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-22:/shine.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another of Janos's great books. Shine is a collection of 'optimistic near-future' sci-fi short stories. The fantastic Alastair Reynolds has a story in there, which lived up to his high standards. Of the people I hadn't heard of the two that stood out were Kay Kenyon with Castoff World and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another of Janos's great books. Shine is a collection of 'optimistic near-future' sci-fi short stories. The fantastic Alastair Reynolds has a story in there, which lived up to his high standards. Of the people I hadn't heard of the two that stood out were Kay Kenyon with Castoff World and Madeline Ashby with Ishin.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Castoff World stuck in my mind because of the atmosphere evoked by the pair adrift in the sea with the nano-swarm. Kenyon brilliantly describes their world.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Ishin we've got an exciting but sensitive tale, which again makes me want to read more of Ashby's work. I didn't like the fact the an otherwise sympathetic character happened to be a patent troll!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Oldfield 20 mph Speed Limit</title><link href="/oldfield-20-mph-speed-limit.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-21T09:48:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-21T09:48:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-21:/oldfield-20-mph-speed-limit.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just responded to the consultation on the &lt;a href="http://www.bathnes.gov.uk/services/streets-and-highway-maintenance/road-safety/traffic-schemes/creating-neighbourhoods-where-p"&gt;20 mph speed limit in Oldfield Park&lt;/a&gt;, voting in favour of it. In the comments section I said that I'd like to see more zebra crossings, particularly at the junction between Livingstone Road and Brougham Hayes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've just responded to the consultation on the &lt;a href="http://www.bathnes.gov.uk/services/streets-and-highway-maintenance/road-safety/traffic-schemes/creating-neighbourhoods-where-p"&gt;20 mph speed limit in Oldfield Park&lt;/a&gt;, voting in favour of it. In the comments section I said that I'd like to see more zebra crossings, particularly at the junction between Livingstone Road and Brougham Hayes.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Archiving</title><link href="/archiving_17.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-17T21:16:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-17T21:16:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-17:/archiving_17.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The boxes left to archive:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="boxes" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_164723.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember painting this when I was at St. Laurence. As you might have deduced I was keen on Karate.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="karate" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_164817.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the Paul Hardcastle hit 19. A bit embarrassing now.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="19" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_164859.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bag" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_164916.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawn by my cousin Giles. This was on the door of my bedroom for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The boxes left to archive:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="boxes" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_164723.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember painting this when I was at St. Laurence. As you might have deduced I was keen on Karate.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="karate" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_164817.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the Paul Hardcastle hit 19. A bit embarrassing now.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="19" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_164859.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bag" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_164916.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawn by my cousin Giles. This was on the door of my bedroom for a long time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sonic" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_165112.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="computer" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120916_165202.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The taxpayer should not have to pay to keep Windows free of malware</title><link href="/the-taxpayer-should-not-have-to-pay-to.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-16T14:32:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-16T14:32:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-16:/the-taxpayer-should-not-have-to-pay-to.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's John Dvorak arguing that the taxpayer &lt;a href="http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2409742,00.asp?kc=PCRSS03079TX1K0000584"&gt;should pay to keep Microsoft Windows free of malware&lt;/a&gt;. This would be an indirect subsidy of Microsoft, when really the solution is for users to switch to a more secure operating system such as Ubuntu. This switch is more likely to happen if …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's John Dvorak arguing that the taxpayer &lt;a href="http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2409742,00.asp?kc=PCRSS03079TX1K0000584"&gt;should pay to keep Microsoft Windows free of malware&lt;/a&gt;. This would be an indirect subsidy of Microsoft, when really the solution is for users to switch to a more secure operating system such as Ubuntu. This switch is more likely to happen if Microsoft has to spend its own money on battling malware, because that puts up the price of its software.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Skipwatch 2012-09-11</title><link href="/skipwatch-2012-09-11.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-11T11:25:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-11T11:25:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-11:/skipwatch-2012-09-11.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Part of the ongoing record of the skip...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120911_100144.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Part of the ongoing record of the skip...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Skip" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120911_100144.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="skip-watch"></category></entry><entry><title>Inspiration for the design of Polifesto</title><link href="/inspiration-for-design-of-polifesto.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-11T11:23:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-11T11:23:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-11:/inspiration-for-design-of-polifesto.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've decided to actually design Polifesto. I'm looking for inspiration at the moment. I took some photos and made some drawings from a café in Oxford. This is the window. Curves are hard to do on web sites. Is that true?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Window" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_173102.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the core of the idea.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ridges" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_173434.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pattern" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_173454.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pattern 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_173502.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table leg …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've decided to actually design Polifesto. I'm looking for inspiration at the moment. I took some photos and made some drawings from a café in Oxford. This is the window. Curves are hard to do on web sites. Is that true?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Window" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_173102.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the core of the idea.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ridges" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_173434.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pattern" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_173454.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pattern 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_173502.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table leg drawn on a napkin.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Table Leg" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_174632.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title></title><link href="/heres-matt-on-bridge-in-oxford-reason-i.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-11T11:17:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-11T11:17:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-11:/heres-matt-on-bridge-in-oxford-reason-i.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's Matt on a bridge in Oxford:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Matt On Bridge" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_144834.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I took it is that the bridge is exactly the same design as the new bridge that's been put up in Linear Park near to me in Bath. I find the design uninspiring. After seeing Victoria Bridge in Bath and the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's Matt on a bridge in Oxford:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Matt On Bridge" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120910_144834.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I took it is that the bridge is exactly the same design as the new bridge that's been put up in Linear Park near to me in Bath. I find the design uninspiring. After seeing Victoria Bridge in Bath and the bridges over the canal in Bath, it's depressing that we can't match or exceed their beauty.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Archiving 2012-09-11</title><link href="/archiving-2012-09-11.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-11T11:12:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-11T11:12:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-11:/archiving-2012-09-11.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was from a box marked, 'fragile: ornaments from piano'. This is a pentagon section box I made. My Dad a bought a job lot of laminated strips of wood. There were hundreds of them. It was perfect for me to make stuff with.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pentagon Box 1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123211.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pentagon Box 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123233.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hinged in the middle …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was from a box marked, 'fragile: ornaments from piano'. This is a pentagon section box I made. My Dad a bought a job lot of laminated strips of wood. There were hundreds of them. It was perfect for me to make stuff with.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pentagon Box 1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123211.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pentagon Box 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123233.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hinged in the middle. I'm impressed with my former self!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pentagon Box 3" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123244.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pentagon Box 4" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123253.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really can't remember why I made this!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Googly Eyes 1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123645.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A creation of pure whimsy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Googly Eyes 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123654.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Googly Eyes 3" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123707.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Doug's.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pasta Face 1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123749.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pasta Face 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_123800.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A whole load of stuff. In the bottom right hand corner is the shell of a firework I made.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Collection 1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_124449.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Collection 2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_124839.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Collection 3" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120909_125247.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Sound Of A Wild Snail Eating</title><link href="/the-sound-of-wild-snail-eating.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-11T10:59:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-11T10:59:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-11:/the-sound-of-wild-snail-eating.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a book that my aunt gave me. The author describes her experience of being confined to her bed for years with an autoimmune disease. She is inspired by watching a snail in a terrarium next to her bed. She muses on the similarities between the life of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a book that my aunt gave me. The author describes her experience of being confined to her bed for years with an autoimmune disease. She is inspired by watching a snail in a terrarium next to her bed. She muses on the similarities between the life of the snail and the life that has been imposed on her. It's a precise and moving description of her experience. Enriching.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Archive</title><link href="/archive_9.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-09T12:26:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-09T12:26:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-09:/archive_9.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's one of the CDT projects I blogged about earlier:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_204650.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jaws of the device:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_204704.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jaws opened by pushing this forward with one's thumb:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt3" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_204712.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holes in the barrel are to make the device lighter:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt4" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_204739.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of the first things I did in CDT and I'm still …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's one of the CDT projects I blogged about earlier:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt1" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_204650.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jaws of the device:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt2" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_204704.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jaws opened by pushing this forward with one's thumb:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt3" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_204712.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holes in the barrel are to make the device lighter:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt4" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_204739.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of the first things I did in CDT and I'm still very proud of it. It's an Oxo cube dispenser. It worked like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seed_drill"&gt;Jethro Tull's seed drill&lt;/a&gt;. You rolled the wheel with your hand, and an Oxo cube dropped out. The slit is to see when the dispenser needs refilling.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt5" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205134.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt6" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205151.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt7" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205212.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt8" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205227.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another CDT project. This was the one that I entered for the exam. It's a desk light. This is the closed, off position.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt9" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205408.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt10" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205417.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt11" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205445.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the switch. It comes on when the shade is put in the 'on' position.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt12" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205503.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt13" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205519.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is in the 'on' position. You can see that by putting it in the 'on' position the switch turns the light on. The lamp is a halogen bulb just by the tube.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="cdt14" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205602.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt15" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205625.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made this hideous weapon. Didn't use them much. When swinging them around I was much more of a danger to myself than anyone else.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cdt16" src="/images/2012/IMG_20120908_205820.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>V For Vendetta</title><link href="/v-for-vendetta.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-09T11:51:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-09T11:51:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-09:/v-for-vendetta.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were standing around the fire-pit, and the conversation turned to Alan Moore. I'd heard a lot about him. I'd watched V For Vendetta, but I'd never read anything of his. Jonathan went and got VfV and From Hell.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a brilliantly written and drawn story. I'd recommend it without …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were standing around the fire-pit, and the conversation turned to Alan Moore. I'd heard a lot about him. I'd watched V For Vendetta, but I'd never read anything of his. Jonathan went and got VfV and From Hell.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a brilliantly written and drawn story. I'd recommend it without reservation. From one point of view it's a clash of two political ideas, authoritarianism and anarchy, both of which I disagree with. I favour democracy. I've written before about the dearth of democracy in fiction. Perhaps it's because it's more exciting to read about things being blown up, than to read about the next meeting of the agriculture sub-committee.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I found myself disagreeing with both V and the Leader. What would I have done? I'd probably not have the courage or ability to do much, but I'd try and be part of a non-violent democracy movement. Easy for me to say from the comfort of my armchair.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am looking forward to the other Moore book Jonathan lent me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="book-review"></category></entry><entry><title>Archive</title><link href="/archive.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-08T20:31:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-09-08T20:31:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tony</name></author><id>tag:None,2012-09-08:/archive.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm running out of space on Picassa (the photo sharing website that Blogger used) so I've started to use Shutterfly to store my photos. Here are batches &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/567"&gt;2012-09-03&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/1568"&gt;2012-09-04&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm running out of space on Picassa (the photo sharing website that Blogger used) so I've started to use Shutterfly to store my photos. Here are batches &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/567"&gt;2012-09-03&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://tlocke.shutterfly.com/pictures/1568"&gt;2012-09-04&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>